<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>maestro</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING> respected musician, esp a conductor </MEANING><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="mus"/></LabelGp><ExCnt><EX> I will never forget the ecstatic moment , after a dozen tumultuous curtain calls at the end of the Resurrection Symphony , when the elderly <b>maestro</b> lifted the heavy score off the stand -- and shook it as vigorously and as high as he was able , in homage to the great composer .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But the noble impresarios naturally did not forget their great <b>maestro</b>at St. Mark's. Monteverdi had composed no operas since 1630 ; now the Grimani commissioned from him an Adone for Giovanni e Paolo ( 1639 )</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>maestro</b> breathes new life into the composer's primitive neo-Stravinskian language .</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>Sitar <b>maestro</b> Ravi Shankar , who composed music for one of Akram's shows , has predicted that one day he will be famous .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Orb track ` Back Side Of The Moon ' speaks for itself , while current Floyd bassist Guy Pratt even guests on ` UF Orb ' alongside ex-Killing Joker Youth and dub <b>maestro</b> Jah Wobble .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING> sb who is recognised as top of a given field </MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Maximum impact through minimum statement is what Armani is all about -- and the <b>maestro</b> himself lives out the philosophy in his personal life .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It was Dunlop's experience matched by Edwards' youthful ambition . In the end it was Edwards who arrived at Metropole corner first on the last lap , and held his advantage to finish ahead of the <b>maestro</b>.</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>Britain's javelin <b>maestro</b> confesses he has no idea when he will be back in action as he struggles with a stubborn injury to his throwing shoulder .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
