<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="60"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>main</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="attr_only"/><MEANING>chief; most important</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Action: JH 4.3 A large number of Exit Questionnaires indicated that whilst it might not be the <b>main</b> reason for leaving, job security was often a factor in staff actively seeking another post before their contracts expired.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The three <b>main</b> points are to keep the seeds cool, but not frozen, dark and to exclude air.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A adventure playground is located next to the <b>main</b> building.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>main</b> characters in the musical were played by current degree students, a recent graduate and two pupils from local grammar schools.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However that argument was lost when all the <b>main</b> political parties accepted the recommendation of the Dearing Report in the mid 1990s that students should bear part of the cost of their higher education.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>main</b> reception area is very impressive and the staff where very friendly and helpful.
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>the main thing is</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>The <b>main</b> thing is that I am running pain free and feel confident about making a comeback.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>that's the main thing</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>I do alright, I try and that's the <b>main</b> thing .
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>a principal pipe which takes water or gas to a building or takes sewage away</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>She said, however, that the utility planned to lay a new <b>main</b> at south end of the Cowal peninsula.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If the incoming <b>main</b> is made of lead, consult a professionally qualified plumber.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There are several stages: Stage 1 - Wherever possible a new <b>main</b> is laid underground close to the old pipeline to be renewed.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>water</COLLOC><COLLOC>gas</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>But this meant Nuttall redirecting telephone lines, power cables and a water <b>main</b> that runs along Scotland road.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>John them went on to list those items which he thought would require more detailed investigation: "In the bank of the canal from Widnes to Winwick there is a gas <b>main</b> (unless it has been abandoned since 1983).
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><XRefCnt><XREF>mains</XREF></XRefCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the mains</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the public supply of water, gas, or electricity</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The supply of water had dried up as the <b>mains</b> had been bombed and the street tank had been used up.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The French, (electricity), Connection, was something I'd allowed to slip too low in my planning priorities and we were unable to hook-up to the <b>mains</b>, (well, big deal, I hear you hardy camping-types say), but it is very annoying to have equipment on board and to be unable to use it.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>If your water is brown in colour it is most likely to be as a result of rusty pipes, either from within your home or from the <b>mains</b> pipes.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>gas</COLLOC><COLLOC>water</COLLOC><COLLOC>electricity</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Almost all older French properties (especially rural) will have a wood burning stove (<b>mains</b> gas is not very common in France).
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>26/05/03 During the last few weeks work has also taken place at the North end of the car park at Maespoeth in readiness for <b>mains</b> water to be provided.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If there is no <b>mains</b> electricity nearby to run the pump, then a renewable energy technology could be ideal, as a grid connection may be expensive and a diesel generator noisy and polluting.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the mains</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the place where a supply of water, gas, or electricity enters a building or room</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>As the circuit is not isolated from the <b>mains</b>, it is ESSENTIAL to use an isolating transformer if you need to connect an instrument such as an oscilloscope.
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>turn sth off at the mains</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>If, despite these precautions, a pipe does burst: Turn off the water supply at the stop-cock Turn off the electricity supply at the <b>mains</b> as there may be a danger of water seeping into the electrical circuits.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>plug sth into the mains</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Extending the life-time of your battery Recommendations Try to keep the notebook plugged into the <b>mains</b> as often as possible It is not recommended to remove the battery completely as Li-Ion batteries prefer to be kept topped rather than left on a shelf.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="elec"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a principal cable carrying electricity</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>electricity</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>It should be noted that although gas or electricity <b>mains</b> pass across or near the site, this may have no relevance to availability of the respective services.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>While they were being asked to trim investment, the Government's own policies were creating additional needs for investment in electricity distribution: airfields and other new defence installations for the Korean mobilisation, for example, required new electricity <b>mains</b>, as did the new housing estates which were a vital part of Labour's drive for electoral popularity.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>a main course</MEANING><ExCnt><EX><b>Mains</b> include everything from the grilled gourmet burger, hand-carved honey-roast ham or steak and mushroom pie.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>For the <b>mains</b> we could not decide, so shared a plate of haddock with mussels and a serving of lamb.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But my <b>main</b> was fillet steak in a champagne, cream and wild mushroom source.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Mains</b> £ 7.25 for fish and cockle pie, Pork fillet in red wine sauce £ 8.50, duck breast £ 9.25.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the main</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><STYLE label="lit"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the open ocean</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Spirit of Mirth, whose chime of bells Shakes on his cap, and sweetly swells Across the Atlantic <b>main</b>, Grant that Mark's laughter never die, That men through many a century May chuckle o'er Mark Twain!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Mithras, God of the Sunset, low on the Western <b>main</b>, Thou descending immortal, immortal to rise again!
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="sailg"/></LabelGp><MEANING>mainsail or mainmast</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>When it it starts gusting 18+ for me (not very big) it pays to sail with the small jib and full <b>main</b> / spinny - its faster than the normal combination.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Hi, I have two suits of sails to donate to a worthy cause...two <b>mains</b>, two very tired jibs to match.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrBlk><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>an eye for the main chance</PHR><VarCnt><VAR>an eye to the main chance</VAR></VarCnt><VarCnt><VAR>an eye on the main chance</VAR></VarCnt></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>an ability to spot one's most advantageous opportunity</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Speer always had an eye for the <b>main</b> chance and the ability to work fast.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Pritchetts, although God-fearing people, never lacked an eye to the <b>main</b> chance , and when in 1850 a building estate in Gurnard came into being Edmund (a Non-Conformist local preacher) started his Elim Brickyard beside the Luck on Gurnard Marsh.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However, the simple life he so readily pursues is soon interrupted when he is mistakenly recruited by SS Counter Espionage to serve under Major Neuheim (Ian Richardson), a man with an eye on the <b>main</b> chance and always prepared to serve the German cause, provided that the cause serves him to equal or additional measure.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>by main force</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>by sheer strength</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>"' You didn't expect us to grab the kids and hold them by <b>main</b> force , did you?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This caused the walls to sink and split, allowing an assault to be made on the breach by <b>main</b> force , hopefully bringing the siege to a speedy conclusion.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You suppose that your son came down from his bed, went, at great risk, to your dressing-room, opened your bureau, took out your coronet, broke off by <b>main</b> force a small portion of it, went off to some other place, concealed three gems out of the thirty-nine, with such skill that nobody can find them, and then returned with the other thirty-six into the room in which he exposed himself to the greatest danger of being discovered.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>in the main</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>mostly</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The present building dates in the <b>main</b> to 1878, though an extra wing was added in 1892.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Frameworks Document caused consternation among unionists, who in the <b>main</b> rejected it as meeting nationalist needs to thedetriment of Northern Ireland's constitutional position within theUnited Kingdom.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But in the <b>main</b>, no, I'm not a fan of Wagner.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt></PhrBlk><CpdBlk><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main beam</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="c_u"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="autom"/><REGION label="non_AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>headlights which are not dipped</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Get your car or van near and switch on the <b>main</b> beam .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Failure to use <b>main</b> beam at night on unlit roads makes it more difficult for following drivers to judge when it is safe to overtake.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You guys use <b>main</b> beams , if I'm not mistaken.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="constr"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a beam which transmits a load directly to a column</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>A damp-proof membrane of bituminous felt must always be placed immediately below the <b>main</b> beam .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>have come up with an efficient and innovative solution, in around half the time projects like these usually take to complete. Birse CL and the City Council adhere to a new civil engineering industry initiative and standard called ECI (Early Contractor Involvement) which vastly improves completion time for major engineering projects. Under the initiative, engineers work more closely with designers to achieve the same high quality targets in less time, said Birse CL Project Manager, Lee Tinkler. All our diversionary traffic systems around the area have operated smoothly given the difficult circumstances and laying the <b>main</b> beams for this bridge represents the half-way stage in the project.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main chance</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>one's most advantageous opportunity</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>" The Hobarts undoubtedly saw a <b>main</b> chance in building the bridge to pull all the traffic from the old Roman Road to the new road which by now was well used, the Priory being adjacent.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>When wishing to gain his end he could plead with pathos and eloquence; but he never lost sight of the "<b>main</b> chance .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The ' <b>main</b> chance ' is never missed by those who want to manipulate.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main clause</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="ling"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a clause that can form a complete sentence on its own</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>A conjunction joins two <b>main clauses</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>E.g: the company whose brand had been copied decided to sue subordinating conjunction a subordinating conjunction is used to join a subordinate clause to a <b>main clause</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A <b>main clause</b> is the clause within a sentence that gives the main sense of the sentence some sentences can have more than one main clause (called a compound sentence ). Grammatically speaking, a clause consists of at least two phrases, a noun phrase which acts as the subject of a finite verb.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main course</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the most substantial course of a meal</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Generous evening meal presented buffet style, with a choice of starters, <b>main</b> courses and desserts.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>main</b> courses are traditional English on the whole  roast shoulder of lamb, lamb's liver and bacon, whole grilled sea bass, fillet of pork stuffed with cranberry and apricot cheese, chicken supreme  with a twist.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>My <b>main</b> course of wild salmon had all the flavour and texture of a fish that's earned its living.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main deck</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="naut"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the uppermost sheltered deck that runs the entire length of a large ship</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>On board there is a restaurant, bar and open-air café on the <b>main</b> deck , sauna, video and book library.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>From the <b>main</b> deck , you either descended the spiral stairs to reasonable sized twin cabins on the lower dolphin deck, or up to the lido deck.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main drag</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/><META label="esp"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the main street in a town</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Despite being hidden away from Blackheath's <b>main</b> drag , this is a hugely popular place &amp;, at around £ 5 for starters &amp; £ 10 for mains (even the prices don't seem to change), it's often necessary to book ahead.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Popular Greenwich local tucked away off the <b>main</b> drag .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Venue Located off the <b>main</b> drag of Regent Street, Absolut Icebar sits at the top of pedestrianised Heddon Street, adjoining Below Zero.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main man</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a close friend</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>After hearing Camby tell Lounsbury, ``You're my <b>main</b> man ,'' the businessman gave Lounsbury tens of thousands of dollars, expecting to be repaid when Camby turned pro _ and hired Lounsbury as his agent.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" Mr Tonkins informed the questioning officer that the man in question was called' Linford ' by his associates and was also introduced to the gentleman with the phrase:' Dis here is me <b>main</b> man Linford Christie, he will sort you out'.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" Yo, my <b>main</b> man !
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main memory</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="c_u"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="IT"/></LabelGp><MEANING>memory that is internal to the computer rather than external sotrage devices</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Up to 40 servers in a standard 72 inch rack provides up to 40 GB of <b>main</b> memory and over 1.4 TB of hot-swappable internal disk storage.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>When I move or delete a program from the <b>main</b> memory of my Palm, I lose all my high scores!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The same dollar investment in more ordinary memory configurations generally will give you a significantly larger <b>main</b> memory .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main road</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>a principal road</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>A road leads from the hotel to the <b>main road</b> in Ballyferriter West.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>' We walked down the <b>main road</b>, and after a while we came to a graveyard in the corner of which were the ruins of an old church.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You had to turn left off the <b>main road</b> and go down a steep hill to get to our house.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main squeeze</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/><STYLE label="hum"/><STYLE label="journ"/></LabelGp><MEANING>sb's romantic partner; sb's boyfriend or girlfriend </MEANING><ExCnt><EX>There's a snapshot of PhilJax and his <b>main</b> squeeze at a Playboy Mansion shindig, for those who need a visual aid ...</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Billy Connolly is more familiar, surely, for his portrayal of the widowed Queen Victoria's <b>main</b> squeeze in Mrs Brown . </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Lace is the <b>main</b> squeeze of tough guy Dominic ( Asher Brauner ) the main man in the Silver Daggers street gang. </EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main street</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the principal street in a town</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>We spent an hour in a coffee shop on the <b>main</b> street listening to the jukebox and sipping coffee, then we headed home.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As I walked down the <b>main</b> street in the city I suddenly realised that the two Indians whom I had seen, one in Warsaw, the other in Berlin, were one and the same person.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>His father had a jewellery shop on the <b>main</b> street of Dún Laoghaire.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><VarCnt><VAR>Main Street</VAR></VarCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>people who live in small towns and are considered to have conservative views</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>``In previous years we probably would have relied on pressure from our (national) group and the other major environmental groups on Congress or the state legislature,'' Hamilton notes, ``but today we look for the support to come from <b>main</b> street .''
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>And even if Wall Street greeted news of the deal with open arms, <b>Main</b> Street seemed a little more wary.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>His ear for the sentiments of Middle America, his ear for its patriotism and practical sense, his ear for what <b>Main</b> Street finds funny or crazy or inspiring.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>main verb</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="ling"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the verb in a clause that is not an auxiliary verb</MEANING><ExCnt><EX> In German however there are two auxiliary verbs for perfect tense : haben and sein . Which verb is used depends on the <b>main verb</b> of the sentence : most require the first , some require the second . </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Key words for the future tense are shall or will before the <b>main verb</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A token consists of one <b>main verb</b> and its associated arguments and adjuncts.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt></CpdBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
