<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>mainly</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adv"/><GRAM code="deg"/><MEANING>more than anything else</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Leeds Methodist Choir, W Yorkshire The choir consists <b>mainly</b> of Methodists from churches in the Leeds District, but membership is open to anyone who wishes to join Leeds Parish Church Choir, W Yorkshire 2 Jul Leeds Philharmonic Society, W Yorkshire One of the leading choirs in the North of England.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Your final degree will depend <b>mainly</b> on the later levels of study.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The homes of a number of RUC members were petrolbombed or otherwise damaged, and several members who lived in <b>mainly</b> Protestant areas had to move out of their homes due to loyalist intimidation and threats made to them and to their families.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The mere replacement of the synagogue is seen by a growing number as financially unwise, but it may be economically practical to rebuild towards the rear of the site, now <b>mainly</b> a car park, and possibly sell off the unoccupied front section for residential development.
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>mainly because</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>For me, chamber music is the work I find the most fulfilling, <b>mainly</b> because it's the most challenging but also because you get to work very closely with people that you count as fast friends.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>mainly due to</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>We had a superb weekend, <b>mainly</b> due to the company and the clement weather (it can be very damp in the Dales but I didn't tell them that before we went!
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adv"/><GRAM code="deg"/><MEANING>in most cases</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Adults are <b>mainly</b> found during May and June but the species has a long season with adults being recorded through to September and October.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>About fifty kids got off the bus together C <b>mainly</b> boys, but some girls.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Today The Kings Hospital, now in Palmerstown, has become one of the most expensive schools in Dublin, educating the sons and daughters of <b>mainly</b> well-off families of different denominations.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
