<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>mainspring</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the principal spring in a clock or other mechanism</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>There can be little doubt that the first watches appeared shortly after 1500, when Peter Henlein, a locksmith in Nürnberg, Ger., introduced the <b>mainspring</b> as a replacement for weights in driving clocks.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They also include fixed jaws intended to allow removal of the <b>mainspring</b> of the lock when stripping it.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A long <b>mainspring</b> with stopwork gives a similar effect.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the main motivating factor or agent</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>My Aunt is the <b>mainspring</b> in this move for Gussie's first reaction is against it.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Barkworth had thought of a series in which money, rather than love or crime, acted as the dramatic <b>mainspring</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Nevertheless it was not the <b>mainspring</b> of the decision, for every member of the House was at pains to emphasise that the submission for the Attorney- General did not depend on giving the injunction any binding effect on The Sunday Times.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>And while overseas trade diversified and extended its geographical horizons, the fact that much of this was import led only serves to re-emphasise the crucial importance of growing domestic demand for goods and services as the <b>mainspring</b> of change.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The same historians will also argue that the unionists will never accept a reunited Ireland so it is better to give in to their minority position while ignoring the fact that the people who compromise the bilk of unionists, the Ulster Presbyterians, were the inspiration and <b>mainspring</b> of Irish republicanism during the 1798 uprising and many continued to play not insignificant roles in subsequent struggles for independence.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>for</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>The parts of the Convention quoted below seem to express the same views as Carol Gill in regard to why disability culture is needed. Preamble: 3. Being aware that cultural diversity creates a rich and varied world which increases the range of choices and nurtures human capacities and values and therefore is a <b>mainspring</b> for sustainable development for communities, peoples and nations; 5. Celebrating the importance of cultural diversity for the full realization of human rights and fundamental freedoms proclaimed in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and other universally recognized instruments; 6. Emphasizing the need to incorporate culture as a strategic element in national and international development policies, as well as in international development cooperation, taking also into account the United Nations Millennium Declaration (2000) with its special emphasis on poverty eradication; 7. Taking into account that culture takes diverse forms across time and space
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The systems that operate or could operate within society, the scientific and technological ideas and devices either real or potential, these provide the <b>mainsprings</b> for a powerful, thoughtful and exciting fiction that is characteristic of the modern age.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>At Ofcom we believe that effectively functioning markets, rather than regulation, are the <b>mainspring</b> for the delivery of innovation, quality and choice for consumers and for citizens.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
