<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="30"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>mainstream</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><MEANING>considered ordinary and accepted or used by most people</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The fledgeling PUP wanted to attract politicalthinkers like Ervine, former loyalist paramilitaries or any other memberof the public who wanted to take a political road but who wereunsympathetic towards <b>mainstream</b> unionist parties.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The album itself is more <b>mainstream</b> than' Royal Hunt' and we get to see the more commercial side of Cooper's vocal ability.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>All of which suggests that the <b>mainstream</b> religions are destined to last for limited periods of time, and have a cultural significance for specific peoples rather than a relevance for the whole of humanity.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Them, a distinctly unglamorous bunch, reflect Morrisons love of the blues: their material is drawn not from <b>mainstream</b> pop but from American folk-blues.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>- Editor I always get slightly embarrassed about this because I am very <b>mainstream</b>, in that I am middle-class, Oxbridge educated, White girl essentially but I count as being diverse because I am also
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the mainstream</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the ideas, activities, methods etc that are considered ordinary and accepted by most people</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>All these curators are convinced that the periphery is as important as the <b>mainstream</b> in contemporary art.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>His decision to go for suspense over characterization certainly panders to the <b>mainstream</b>, but it is a pandering one cannot but enjoy.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This play is difficult to stage and has not been done that often for a Keane play, but I like work that is a little away from the <b>mainstream</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>George Alagiah says, "I wanted to fit in and become English "24 April 2006 In advance of publishing his book "Home from Home" about immigration to the UK, BBC News Presenter George Alagiah said, "I'll be comparing my experience, the integrationalist approach, with the experience of immigrants who come here and grow up in a community that is somewhat removed from the <b>mainstream</b> of British society.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But their patron, though ensconced in the Prime Minister's palace, is clearly more estranged from the <b>mainstream</b> of Catholic politics than at any time in his 40-year career.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>And as part and parcel of these developments, the profession of psychiatry itself has been edging out of the unnatural confinement in which it has traditionally been kept and is trying, with uneven success, to join the <b>mainstream</b> of American life.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to bring something into the mainstream</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Our aim is to <b>mainstream</b> this important objective in the Union's relations with the wider world.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It has taken some time to <b>mainstream</b> this issue.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There is much information and many examples of good practice exist when it comes to developing sustainable buildings but they are not being <b>mainstreamed</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Staffordshire Adult Mental Health NSF Partnership, in publishing these standards, have anticipated this duty and have made a clear step forward in <b>mainstreaming</b> women's mental health.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>relating to children who do not have special needs</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Willington Action for Youth - £ 28,000 Towards the costs of a Learning Mentor to help re-integrate young people who have been excluded from school or <b>mainstream</b> education.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The changes in preparation the special education teachers and <b>mainstream</b> teachers had to be indentified after 1989.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Children at her current <b>mainstream</b> school learned to accept Rebecca and their fear of disability went away naturally.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the mainstream</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>education for children who do not have special needs</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>" Sending them into these classes without the proper support and back up is a waste of time, that child has no idea how to survive in the <b>mainstream</b>," the spokesman claimed.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If ever you have thought about educating outside the <b>mainstream</b>, you will want to look at this site.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>According to Stainback and Stainback (1988), an inclusive school is one that educates all students in the <b>mainstream</b>; and provides them with appropriate facilities and materials.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to include children with special needs in ordinary schools or classes</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>International Perspectives on <b>Mainstreaming</b> Children with Special Educational Needs.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Mainstreaming</b> children with Visual Handicaps; Mainstreaming children with Physical handicaps; Mainstreaming children with Mental Handicaps; Mainstreaming children with Hearing-Impairments; Mainstreaming children with Learning Disabilities; Mainstreaming children with Speech and Language Impairments; Mainstreaming children with Emotional Disturbances; Mainstreaming children with Health Impairments.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Brownell, M.T. &amp; Pajares, F. (1999) Teacher efficacy and perceived success in <b>mainstreaming</b> students with learning and behaviour problems, Teacher Education and Special Education, 22(3), pp.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>mainstreaming</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the inclusion of children with special needs in ordinary schools and classes</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Attitudes of elementary classroom teachers toward <b>mainstreaming</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Mainstreaming</b> means that schools &amp; nurseries may have one or two deaf children?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As to the other content areas -- the teacher's attitudes toward <b>mainstreaming</b>, it has been found that these have a major effect on the actual success of mainstreaming (B.Cook, Tankersley, L.Cook, &amp; Landrum, 2000 ). Findings of teachers ' attitudes tend to be inconsistent, with some studies showing positive attitudes, while other studies show negative attitudes (Villa, Thousand, Meyers, &amp; Nevin, 1996; Yasutake &amp; Lerner, 1996 ). In the third area, two terms have been used in the research literature to discuss personality attributes of the teacher who is successful at mainstreaming -- the teacher's
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><VarCnt><VAR>mainstream jazz</VAR></VarCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="mus"/></LabelGp><MEANING>jazz that is not traditional or modern, based on the 1930s swing style</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>JAZZ JAMAICA. doors 7pm ... www.meanfiddler.com BBC - Radio 3 - Jazz Featuring all types of jazz from <b>mainstream</b> to the new generation of up-and-coming players.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The next recital in the series will take place on Monday 8 November when the Billy Thom Band will play swinging mainstream <b>jazz</b> from 12.30-1.15pm.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There's mainstream <b>jazz</b> at The Bustard, South Rauceby.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
