<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>mainstay</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>someone or something which something is based on or depends on</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Although tourism is the economic <b>mainstay</b>, there is some other industry, including printing and electronics and the production of paper, cheese, textiles, and animal foodstuffs.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Irishman who came to Hillsborough as a' development player' has been a <b>mainstay</b> in Paul Sturrock's squad in recent weeks despite not hitting the target.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>One of the <b>mainstays</b> was lutfisk, which was always served with boiled potatoes and a white sauce.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Burn FM was first launched in 1995, and since then has become a <b>mainstay</b> of student life.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Surgery is the <b>mainstay</b> of treatment for varicose veins in many patients.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The lecture discusses the conflict between fishermen and marine mammals and how it is managed in an area where fishing is still the <b>mainstay</b> of the economy and marine mammals are by many seen as competitors for scarce resources, even as pest.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Sedums and hardy fuchsias are <b>mainstays</b> of my October garden.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>Doxorubicin, a <b>mainstay</b> drug of chemotherapy, can cause heart damage, while another anti-cancer agent, cis-platinum, can harm the kidneys.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Glenn Stephenson, J.C. Nichols ' director of asset management and leasing, said the company needed a mix of <b>mainstay</b> shops like the Gap and one-of-a-kind stores like Pinstripes.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The multinationals have also helped the growth of <b>mainstay</b> industries in the metropolis.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="sailg"/><DOMAIN label="naut"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a stay which stretches from the maintop to the bottom of the foremast of a sailing boat</MEANING></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
