<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="30"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>mainline</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><VarCnt><VAR>main line</VAR></VarCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="attr_only"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="transp"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a principal railway line</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>He made particular reference to the East Coast <b>mainline</b>, the prospects for the re-use of the Leamside line and the fact that there were no proposed improvements at stations, particularly at Sunderland.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>main</b> line links Taunton with the south west peninsular of England, London and the rest of the UK.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Town-centre location close to Witham rail station on the <b>main</b> line between London Liverpool Street and Norwich.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="attr_only"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="transp"/></LabelGp><MEANING>relating to a principal raillway line</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>A direct <b>mainline</b> Virgin train service runs from the airport's train station to Stoke-on-Trent.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They are suggesting that the double rail line, which already exists connecting Dublin s <b>mainline</b> rail terminals via the Phoenix Park tunnel, be used instead.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Then he got busted in a men's lavatory in a <b>mainline</b> railway station.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="attr_only"/><LabelGp><META label="esp"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>mainstream</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>There are many formerly' missionary ' areas where all of the <b>mainline</b> churches have tacitly settled for their present limited' slice of the cake '.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Mr Curran also condemned allegations by Councillor Danny Kennedy that this was "the work of splinter or <b>mainline</b> republican groups".
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Liberal presuppositions Why then is the case for Mosaic authorship of Deuteronomy ignored by <b>mainline</b> scholars?
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><LabelGp><STYLE label="drugs"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to inject illegal drugs into a vein</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>He was <b>mainlining</b> heroin by the second series of Playschool and it was all the producers could do to keep him out of the tabloids.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However, when it comes to drugs, they know their business and I'm soon <b>mainlining</b> warm fluid and morphine.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Nor does the careful public figure admit to smoking pot or snorting cocaine or, heaven forfend, <b>mainlining</b> heroin; those verbs are too vivid.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Mainlined</b> it, I did, and it blew me bleedin mind.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="_0"/><ExCnt><EX>It is a bit like an addict <b>mainlining</b> with strychnine rather than heroin because it is a white powder.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But when I actually <b>mainlined</b> into my vein that's when I thought, wow, this is it.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>mainlining</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><STYLE label="drugs"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the act of injecting illegal drugs into a vein</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Intravenous injection (' <b>mainlining</b>') is when the heroin solution is injected directly into the human blood vessel.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX> It is like <b>mainlining</b> . For many people , once they start with it they are addicted and cannot stop the habit even if they wanted to .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It's <b>mainlining</b> that leaves scars.'
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to do, eat, or drink too much of something</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>I didn't end up applying to Selwyn as the college now just makes me think of <b>mainlining</b> Lemsip, but all in all, the scheme was reassuring and confirmed what I already knew: that I wanted to apply.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I chose the halloumi and grilled vegetable shish kebab, mainly because I am <b>mainlining</b> squeaky cheese at the moment, and my sidekick for the evening chose burger and chips, to give a well rounded vegetarian / meat eaters verdict of Nora?s.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He's excited by the prospect of ``yuppies talking on their cell phones and <b>mainlining</b> caffeine as they shop.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The very idea has such intoxicating appeal that the program has become the one for which the foundation is best known, a source of fascination that one MacArthur official likened to ``<b>mainlining</b> the American myth.''
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
