<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="40"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>maintenance</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the process of keeping something in good condition</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>A single barrel loaded with numerous bullets - without the use of a magazine, automatic detachment of cartridge cases or any other kind of mechanical function - is actually a complete weapon, which requires very little <b>maintenance</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A soft-tail custom, he keeps it in immaculate condition, every spare moment given to polishing, cleaning and <b>maintenance</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The one place that was off limits for us as children was the disused basin of the decaying naval dockyard where some big old tankers were moored to the jetty, awaiting disposal, and where Uncle Bob was the engineer in charge of <b>maintenance</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>do</COLLOC><COLLOC>carry out</COLLOC><COLLOC>perform</COLLOC><COLLOC>undertake</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Once he had to do some <b>maintenance</b> to his Windmill and remove the sails.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>All <b>maintenance</b> is carried out to a very high standard by our own team of qualified engineers.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A gas turbine's power advantages are offset to some extent by its need for routine maintenance and its high servicing costs The owner of a gas turbine power plant is not generally in the business of gas turbines so has neither the ability nor desire to perform the <b>maintenance</b> themselves.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Further restoration and <b>maintenance</b> was undertaken in 1980-81 by the Odiham Society with a view to its subsequent use as a mini heritage centre housing artifacts of local interest.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>need</COLLOC><COLLOC>require</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>MAINTENANCE AND REPAIR All buildings need maintenance in the same way that vehicles need <b>maintenance</b> to keep them safe and working efficiently.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However, the turf will require additional <b>maintenance</b> e.g. aeration by spiking to replace the beneficial effects of earthworms and keep it in a healthy condition.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>routine</COLLOC><COLLOC>general</COLLOC><COLLOC>essential</COLLOC><COLLOC>regular</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Routine <b>maintenance</b> such as replacing broken carriage windows is also occupying us in the run up to the busy Santa season Our next restoration project, NER 831, is being run over with a fine tooth comb and we have started loosening doors ready to be opened for the first time since 1909!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>' The insurance, petrol and general <b>maintenance</b> was stretching our budget and since both me and my husband work locally, it seemed a bit mad to hang on to it.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Please note that due to essential <b>maintenance</b>, from Jan 2006 - May 2007 disabled access will be via the North side of the Cathedral.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Without regular <b>maintenance</b>, their condition often deteriorates before a new use can be identified, leading in some cases to their demolition.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>low</COLLOC><COLLOC>high</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Created for the needs of disabled gardeners, with easy acess and low <b>maintenance</b>, the garden has special surfaces to make walking or wheelchair use easy, and brings you in through a sluice gate where you are surrounded by walls of water.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Like many people, I had been smitten with the Ducati 916 ever since it first appeared in 1994, but like most people, could not afford one and, already owning one of the most reliable well built superbikes, was not ready to exchange this for the (reputed) dubious build quality and high <b>maintenance</b> associated with the Ducati, even if they do sound and look drop dead gorgeous.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>A disproportionate amount of clergy time is spent on administering the parish and on the <b>maintenance</b> of churches, halls and rectories and since many of these are old buildings maintenance is a continuous job.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The best way to ensure electrical safety is to prevent faults from developing by regular <b>maintenance</b> of equipment and ensuring that the distribution is in the hands of an experienced individual.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>These include a comprehensive parking strategy (including a workplace parking levy in the city), re-allocating road space to favour buses, pedestrians, and cyclists, regulating the flow of traffic using computerised traffic signals, encouraging organisations to put Travel Plans into practice, and working with freight operators to reduce the impact of freight traffic. &amp;nbsp;Better transport facilities and services This includes investing in better public transport, providing better facilities for pedestrians and cyclists, better &lt;b&gt;maintenance&lt;/b&gt; of roads, footways, lighting and bridges, and measures to improve road safety.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>Vehicle <b>maintenance</b> was constant, with daily checks being carried out in order to keep the massive armoured fleet operational.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The successful applicant will be part of the team responsible for space planning / design, building <b>maintenance</b> and refits and property acquisitions and disposals.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Regional Development Road Maintenance (Ards Borough Council Area) Mr Shannon asked the Minister for Regional Development to clarify what proportion of financial assistance is allocated for road <b>maintenance</b> and improvement in the Ards Borough Council area, compared with other local government authorities.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>The Docklands Authority took ownership of the Jeanie Johnston tall ship in September 2005 and the ship is currently moored at Dublin City Moorings in Dublin's Docklands where it is undergoing its winter <b>maintenance</b> programme.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Properly installed and maintained, valves will work well, but the householder or <b>maintenance</b> staff must carry out regular tests if leaks are to be spotted.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This charity operates 45 teams of dedicated <b>maintenance</b> workers, who tour the country's historic buildings carrying out agreed maintenance plans and immediate temporary repairs, advising owners on any further work required.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>work</COLLOC><COLLOC>costs</COLLOC><COLLOC>contract</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Society volunteers now carry out some <b>maintenance</b> work such as tree clearance, towpath re-surfacing, piling, and building overflow weirs.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Our professional team skillfully manufacture horseboxes with full integral features and capability to tilt the cab for ease of access to maintain the vehicle engine, thus keeping <b>maintenance</b> costs down, especially if you are long haul users, this is why we are popular with top Racehorse Trainers and Transporters who are always on the go and want their box in and out of the garage.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In April last year around 17 % of our customers had a <b>maintenance</b> contract with us.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the process of continuing something or keeping it in existence</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>N UNIFIL - Lebanon Operates under Chapter 6 of the UN Charter ' The Security Council may at any stage of a dispute recommend appropriate procedures or methods of adjustment ' KFOR - Kosovo Assembled pursuant to Chapter 8 of the UN Charter ' Nothing in the Charter precludes the existence of regional arrangements or agencies for dealing with the <b>maintenance</b> of international peace and security, but no enforcement measures shall be undertaken without the authorization of the Security Council ' UNTAET - East Timor Operates under Chapter 7 of the UN Charter ' The Security Council may take such action by air, sea, or land forces as may be necessary to maintain or restore international peace and security' The reputation of the Irish soldier on peacekeeping missions is held in high regard, as we see in Kosovo.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A knowledge of modern warfare was their chief contribution to the <b>maintenance</b> of law and order.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>True to his principles, and with good grace on both sides, he desisted from involving the diocese of Clonfert (united with Killaloe form 1834) when Bishop Sandes informed him that he did not want to place upon his clergy' any restraint which may not appear essential to the <b>maintenance</b> of episcopal authority.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the provision of financial support for a person's living expenses</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>So in their turn the Northbrook Road premises were sold, and the money used to endow the Methodist Female Orphan School Trust which paid for the education and <b>maintenance</b> at Wesley College of girls who would otherwise have qualified for the school.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Up to six Berrow Foundation Scholarships, which also cover fees and <b>maintenance</b> for up to three years, are open to those of Swiss, or Liechtenstein, nationality who are graduates of the Swiss Universities of Berne, Geneva, Lausanne, Fribourg, Neuchatel or Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne, and who are fluent in written and spoken English.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>allowance</COLLOC><COLLOC>grant</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The scholarships will cover UK/EU tuition fees and a <b>maintenance</b> allowance of £ 9,000.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="law"/></LabelGp><MEANING>financial support given by someone to their ex-spouse after separation or divorce, especially to pay for the care of children</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>In these cases, the bitterness is expressed in reduced co-operation regarding access to children, threats to prevent future access, rows over <b>maintenance</b> and the occasional exchange of insults.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Under such laws a woman who lived with a man would have a right to financial support after a break-up in the same way the wife can claim <b>maintenance</b> after a divorce .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is therefore likely that much of the legal authority that has developed in case law, governing the division of property and the provision of spousal <b>maintenance</b> on divorce , will also apply to civil partnerships.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>pay</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>It is common enough, for example, for a spouse to say, "Well, you're not paying me enough <b>maintenance</b> so you are not going to see the children.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Answered by: Tracy McCormack, Solicitor 13 May 2001 Q. My ex husband was ordered to pay £ 12,000 per year <b>maintenance</b> when he divorced me in 1996.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>child</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>CSA refused to offset Mr X's maintenance payments against the £ 1,616.41 arrears, on the grounds that they had no jurisdiction over payments under a court order and that the parent with care had said she had received no child <b>maintenance</b> during the initial period.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>payment</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>13.9 1994 On 24 January 1994 Dudley again told Mr X that his <b>maintenance</b> payments were in arrears.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>order</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The non-resident parent did not cooperate, but CSA delayed for fourteen months before imposing an interim <b>maintenance</b> order .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
