<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>mainland</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the mainland</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the mass of land that forms the main part of a country on continent but does not include any islands</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>I put my shoes and shirt back on, collect our towels and stuff my posessions into Martin's holdall, then Martin and I are waylaid by a woman telling us her boat hasn't come to pick her up, and could we call her hotel when we reach the <b>mainland</b>?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Numerous vedettes travel backwards and forwards between the islands and the <b>mainland</b>, but it is only possible to land on one of the islands, Ile aux Moines, the others are all part of the nature reserve.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Taiwan officials are only allowed to visit the <b>mainland</b> for international events and relations between the two have been sour since a June trip to the US by Taiwanese President Lee Teng-hui.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>Chinese</COLLOC><COLLOC>Scottish</COLLOC><COLLOC>European</COLLOC><ETC/></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Typhoon Rananim-confirmed by China's meteorological authorities to be the strongest to hit the Chinese <b>mainland</b> since 1956.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The melting of the ice caps released millions of gallons of fresh water which subsequently drowned the land bridge and created what is now called the English Channel - the point which seperates Britain from the European <b>mainland</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>name of country or state</COLLOCTYPE><ExCnt><EX>Delivery Area - most parts of the UK Both our standard delivery service and guaranteed next-day service apply to the majority of the UK <b>mainland</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>While the US <b>mainland</b> had not been physically damaged, the country still had made sacrifices.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Here, we explore the region's highlights from Key West, in the far south-west, to Key Largo, just off the Florida <b>mainland</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="pertnm"/><MEANING>relating to the mainland</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>We can only ship to UK <b>mainland</b> addresses, in some cases it is possible to arrange delivery to a courier of your choice in the UK and have the goods forwarded to you.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The academic programme will take place at the Franklin Wilkins building, King's College London on the banks of the River Thames, very near Waterloo station (including the Waterloo International Terminal, which serves Eurostar trains coming from <b>mainland</b> Europe).
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Aberdeen has good transport links as the airport has frequent British Airways, BMI and Eastern Airways flights to 15 <b>mainland</b> destinations.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
