<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="50"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>maintain</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to keep a situation or conditions the same</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Our main aims are to: provide advice and support relating to any adverse effects of work on health or health on work support managers in their responsibility for <b>maintaining</b> the health, safety and welfare of staff ensure that University achieves best practice in the management of occupational health risks. reduce ill-health absence and the incidence of work-related ill health.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Both old elites held on in one form or another and, to a greater or lesser degree, <b>maintained</b> their old systems of social organisation and governance, and retained the loyalty of tenants and clients.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Largely isolated in recent centuries from the mainstream of European and Irish economic, social and cultural change, Dingle, in common with other parts of the west of Ireland, long <b>maintained</b> traditional values and customs.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Mayor felt that with the present traffic volume, that there was a need for a one way system in the town and also to <b>maintain</b> the residential character of the streets.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to keep communicating with someone in order to preserve a relationship</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>" Lynch said, "Mychal was unique in that he risked a lot in what he did, and he was extraordinary in his ability to <b>maintain</b> ties with the most sanctimonious of our opponents in the Church.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>contact</COLLOC><COLLOC>links</COLLOC><COLLOC>relationship</COLLOC><COLLOC>relations</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>When I moved' up-north' we <b>maintained</b> contact for a number of years, spending hours on the telephone.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We <b>maintain</b> strong links with all the major shooting and countryside associations and encourage our members to adopt all that is correct, responsible and safe when shooting.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Job Title: Lone Parent Personal Consultants ref LPPC273 Location: Brent Salary: circa £ 25k + Benefits + Achievement Bonus Closing Date: 4th August 2006 Job purpose: To establish and <b>maintain</b> excellent relationships with jobseekers, understanding and meeting their needs in the belief that Working Links can help everyone towards the world of work.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However, co-operating and <b>maintaining</b> good relations with the many branches of Lebanese officialdom certainly presents new challenges, as will working with international organisations and NGOs.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to keep something at the same level, standard, or rate</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Recommendations 8. More in depth health and safety objectives should be set to develop and <b>maintain</b> performance levels.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The duties of the SO are in general to co-ordinate PSS matters in their area of responsibility, to devise appropriate PSS programmes to meet the needs of their Brigade / Service such as Pre-Retirement courses, to <b>maintain</b> the standards of the service and to provide management supervision.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Joint Association of Classical Teachers JACT is a registered charity that aims to improve and <b>maintain</b> the quality of the teaching of classics.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Cook fish in batches to <b>maintain</b> oil temperature .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to keep information about something</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>record</COLLOC><COLLOC>list</COLLOC><COLLOC>database</COLLOC><COLLOC>register</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>This department <b>maintains</b> a record of restrictive covenants, rights and mortgages relating to unregistered land.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Dean of Students <b>maintains</b> a list of religious advisers and, within the Students ' Union, there are a number of very active religious and cultural societies which meet on a regular basis.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We also have a sex education programme in schools. These days the government <b>maintains</b> a comprehensive database of those infected and their chain of sexual partners; and although patients are still required to attend an eight-week course in a sanatorium, HIV testing is no longer compulsory  though it is strongly recommended for pregnant women and those in high-risk groups.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Inspectorate <b>maintains</b> a register of Inspectors who are and who are not Freemasons, as well as of those who have declined to provide this information.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to keep a building, road or machine in good repair</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Revenue from motor tax is used to <b>maintain</b> and upgrade the road network.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The present job of <b>maintaining</b> the Cathedral requires the full time employment of many craftsmen, including carpenters and stone masons.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>MECHANIC William Smith was employed to <b>maintain</b> the machinery on the farm.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>well maintained</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>As a much used church enjoying a vibrant ministry throughout the century, it has been well <b>maintained</b> so that, while a disappointment to the modern liturgical purist, it is widely acknowledged as a beautiful church, a haven of peace in a bustling city and, above all, a place of prayer.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>-maintained</SUBFORM><POS code="ptp_adj"/><GRAM code="comb"/><MEANING>used with adverbs such as 'well' or 'poorly' for saying whether something is kept in good repair or not</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Officers also warned of the importance of keeping fire-safety equipment well-maintained, after <b>poorly-maintained</b> smoke alarms failed to detect the danger ... Read full story Two escape copter crash 13th May 2006 Two men had a lucky escape last night after their helicopter caught fire and crash-landed in a remote field, fire officials said.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This spacious and <b>well-maintained</b> holiday home is beautifully situated in an undisturbed area with meadows.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Poorly-installed or <b>badly-maintained</b> gas appliances and flues caused the majority of these incidents.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to provide someone with what they need to live</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>It is to be remembered, however, that there were often difficulties in raising the stipend of the minister in a small or poor congregation and the Synod was concerned to ensure that a congregation could <b>maintain</b> a minister.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If you are a guardian of a child, you have a duty to <b>maintain</b> and properly care for the child and you have a right to make decisions about the child's religious and secular education, health requirements and general welfare.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You can claim an extra allowance for each of your dependent children under age 18 who normally live with and are being <b>maintained</b> by you.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP_refl"/><ExCnt><EX>The success of the Twentieth Century Fund suddenly awakened the British to the fact that the Irish were able to <b>maintain</b> themselves, and that the grant should cease.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is a primary condition of entry into the state for students that they are in a position to <b>maintain</b> themselves while studying here.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This credit is granted to a taxpayer who maintains, at his / her own expense, any person who comes within any of the following categories: * a relative of the taxpayer or taxpayer's spouse who, because of old age or infirmity, is incapable of <b>maintaining</b> himself / herself * the widowed mother of the taxpayer or spouse whether she is incapacitated or not
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to keep a military unit supplied with what it needs</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Britain has had little choice but to <b>maintain</b> a full army garrison and a squadron of attack helicopters in the country.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Where was the Government, still heavily burdened with debts arising out of the Napoleonic Wars, to find upwards of £ 20,000,000 - a sum not far short of the annual cost of <b>maintaining</b> the army , the navy and, indeed, of running the entire country?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>(Four centuries later US troops faced much the same problem in Vietnam's Mekong delta.) Without the co-operation of local populations, the logistical problems of <b>maintaining</b> an army in the field were overwhelming, and after four years the Spanish had to accept that the Dutch-speaking peoples of Holland and Zeeland, and of much of the other northern provinces, had effectively turned them into a' no-go area '.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to state firmly that something is true, especially when other people have suggested it isn't</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="that_0"/><ExCnt><EX>Bosch <b>maintains</b> that in early Christian times many people found the life and worship of the Christian community very attractive.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He <b>maintains</b> he is innocent, saying Saddam, not he, controlled the chemical stockpiles.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" Noel Coward used to <b>maintain</b> that his refusal to come clean about being gay sprang from a solicitous wish not to disillusion all those harmless middle-aged ladies in Goring-by-Sea who ' harboured secret desires' for him.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="Quo"/><ExCnt><EX>These ' empires of religion ', he <b>maintains</b>, whether Islamic, Christian, Hindu or Buddhist, can be compared with nation states in their attention to centralised authority, expansion of bureaucracies, harnessing of print media and scale of building.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Nor can it consistently be on Leibniz's view since he subscribes to a version of psychological egoism; "for we do all for our own good," he <b>maintains</b>, "and it is impossible for us to have other feelings whatever we may say" (W," Letter to Nicaise," p. 565).
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>maintain one's innocence</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>He has <b>maintained</b> his innocence throughout the trial.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><CpdBlk><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>maintained school</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a school that is financed with public money</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>As Gordon Brown aims to set aside future funding, so that as much is spent per pupil in <b>maintained</b> schools as in the independent sector, there should now be the opportunity to provide those from poorer backgrounds with independent education through state funding alongside bursaries and scholarships from independent providers.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As reading and spelling remain a problem for many children the "look and say "method has to given way to "synthetic phonics" and the recently introduced literacy hour in <b>maintained</b> schools looks like being scrapped.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Examples of financial help include:- free school meals school milk school clothing school transport visiting a pupil at a <b>maintained</b> special school.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt></CpdBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
