<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>majesty</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the quality of being impressive in scale, beauty or power</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>I have seen The Great Hornbill many times before but each time I do, the power and <b>majesty</b> of such a magnificent creature is so breathtaking to me!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>His subsequent further study of theology imbued with nominalism led him to feel that the human being is as nothing before the <b>majesty</b> of God's will, and a journey he made to Rome (1510-1511) convinced him that the Church urgently needed reform.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Since coming to Wales she has discovered the beauty of the landscape, the <b>majesty</b> of the seaside, and the joy of curry.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Footpaths head off in many directions from the village, and are popular with walkers who enjoy the spectacular and unspoilt coastal views and the rugged <b>majesty</b> of the cliffs and heathlands of Exmoor.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrBlk><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>His Majesty</PHR><VarCnt><VAR>Her Majesty</VAR></VarCnt><LabelGp><STYLE label="spok"/><REGIST label="fml"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>a way of talking about a king or queen</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>These specify that: • the Commissioner will be nominated by the Parliament and appointed by Her <b>Majesty</b>; • the appointment will be for a period of five years; • the same candidate can be appointed for a second period, whether or not consecutive, but no more than twice.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>At the east-end of St. Pauls, one of the children of Christ-Church Hospital made a speech likewise, with both which Her Majesty seemed very well pleased; Her Majesty was pleased to stand in Cheapside to see the procession pass, and then went to Guild-Hall, where Her <b>Majesty</b> was entertained with the greatest joy and magnificence that it was possible for loyal subjects to shew to their most Gracious Sovereign.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>; Principal of the Univ., and chaplain to His <b>Majesty</b>; called 9th Sept.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>Your Majesty</PHR><LabelGp><STYLE label="spok"/><REGIST label="fml"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>a way of addressing a king or queen</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Herald: Why is that, Your <b>Majesty</b>?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" "Your <b>majesty</b>'s orders shall be instantly carried out.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>31 The Ethiopian came and said, " Your <b>Majesty</b>, today I have good news!
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt></PhrBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
