<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="40"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>majority</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><GRAM code="v_sg_pl"/><MEANING>the greater number or part </MEANING><LINK>be in the majority</LINK><ExCnt><EX>And while initially some units did manage to occupy a number of former British military and police barracks, the <b>majority</b> either continued to live at home or were billeted in safe houses across the countryside.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The ordinary Irish-speaking <b>majority</b> in the country was devastated through mass starvation and emigration.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>majority</b> were not Church of Ireland, only two or three in a class of twenty.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>The <b>majority</b> of the officers had been killed or wounded and it was obvious to Colonels Kelly and Byrnes that it was over, the Brigade could not go on.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Firstly, it was an international war being fought for the British crown, between James, whose wife was Catholic and who was favoured by most Irish, English, and Scottish Catholics, and Dutchman William of Orange, who was favoured by the <b>majority</b> of Protestants.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>majority</b> of the population lived along the coast as most of the hinterland was heavily forested and the mountains in the east prevented expansion in that direction.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Of course since the situation has changed so also has the terminology and these OPs are now referred to as PBs (patrol bases) in recognition of the fact that Unifil in its new deployment actually undertakes the <b>majority</b> of observation tasks.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>' The Alouette attracted the <b>majority</b> of the attention, having been in Air Corps service since 1963, as the British public not really getting a chance to see an Alouette III since the Dutch started to retire their examples a couple of years ago.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>vast</COLLOC><COLLOC>great</COLLOC><COLLOC>overwhelming</COLLOC><COLLOC>large</COLLOC><COLLOC>huge</COLLOC><COLLOC>substantial</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>As October draws to a close, the vast <b>majority</b> of the stags have finished with the rut.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They were not an attempt to reconcile the possibly conflicting views of different members, but to assert that communities live rather by debate than by confrontation, and that conviction has commanded the support of the great <b>majority</b> of the Methodist people in Northern Ireland and in the Republic.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Our findings are also in line with Fahey and Lyons ' conclusion that post-separation, children reside with their mother in the overwhelming <b>majority</b> of cases.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Also, a large <b>majority</b> of those asked in both countries (63 % of French voters, and 68 % of Dutch voters) would like to take back powers from the EU, and in some cases leave it altogether.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The huge <b>majority</b> of our stock is genuine Volvo parts but in a few cases we offer alternatives where experience and common sense proves that safe, superior and value for money options exist.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A substantial <b>majority</b> of respondents agreed that the current remuneration structure was entirely appropriate for providing pharmaceutical care and that if the contract were changed to provide for pharmaceutical care the focus for the majority of community pharmacists would change.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>small</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The small <b>majority</b> who had remained faithful to the Covenants had maintained their testimony in Covenanting societies in Scotland and in Ulster where they had resulted from the ministry of David Houston who died in 1696.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>the silent majority</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>But hopefully we'll see a cultural change: the silent unsmoking <b>majority</b> who don't like smokey environments but put up with them in an uncomplaining and British way will eventually tire of it.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>opinion</COLLOC><COLLOC>view</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX><b>Majority</b> opinion in Tzarist Russia was certainly anti-semitic, and in Hitlerite Germany the policy of anti-semitism may well have had majority support, for educational, political and racial brainwashing can bend the minds of citizens to suit their political or religious rulers.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If, however, the intention was to reach a <b>majority</b> view on the way forward then unanimity may not be required.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>decision</COLLOC><COLLOC>verdict</COLLOC><COLLOC>vote</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>He was of the opinion that the <b>majority</b> decision of the residents should be accepted.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A jury decided by a <b>majority</b> verdict of eight to seven that Gair was guilty.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>9.3 The votes of individual Panel members shall always be treated as confidential and there shall be no disclosure either of such votes or of information showing whether the decision was reached by a unanimous or a <b>majority</b> vote.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>support</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Taking these two figures together, <b>majority</b> support for Gaelic-medium education can be claimed.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>stake</COLLOC><COLLOC>share</COLLOC><COLLOC>shareholder</COLLOC></CollocGp><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="bus-adm"/></LabelGp><ExCnt><EX>" HOW CHANNEL 4 IS WIDENING ITS FOCUS - Channel 4 acquired a <b>majority</b> stake in digital station Oneword, its first investment in radio, in March last year.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Ericsson will own the <b>majority</b> share in the new company and will provide its Wireless Application Protocol (WAP) stack to Microsoft and adopt Microsoft Mobile Explorer for feature phones.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>1987 Ford becomes a <b>majority</b> shareholder in Aston Martin Lagonda Ltd. 1988 Ford launches the Probe.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="pol"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the number of votes by which a person or party wins an election</MEANING><LINK>majority rule</LINK><ExCnt><EX>It was, of course, home rule in a much smaller area, and one in which they could be assured a <b>majority</b> for the foreseeable future, and they set about the business of ensuring that it should be as long a future as possible.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>FT (Philip Stevens) Philip Stevens writes: âLynton Crosby, the Australian political consultant in charge of the Tory campaign, started from the premise that encouraging a low turnout was the best way to cut Labour 's <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>have</COLLOC><COLLOC>hold</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>For 2005, all the winning party will need is 324 MP's to have an overall <b>majority</b> in Parliament.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The pro-Iranian United Iraqi Alliance holds a <b>majority</b> in the new parliament while the US backed parties have sunk into obscurity.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>win</COLLOC><COLLOC>secure</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The film opens in 1920  two years after the Irish nationalists Sinn Fein had won a huge <b>majority</b> in the new Irish parliament.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Thanks to an agreement which was not completed until just before the Commons began to debate a motion of no confidence tabled by the Conservative leader, Mrs Thatcher, the Government secured a comfortable <b>majority</b> of 24 in the ultimate Commons division.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>increase</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>But I stil wish them well and would honestly like to see them become the official opposition. p3t3 is right I think about the voting intentions and how everyone votes in an opinion poll, if everyone voted last time then Labour would have increased their <b>majority</b> and the Tories would have been left with just a hard rump of seats.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>clear</COLLOC><COLLOC>large</COLLOC><COLLOC>substantial</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Labour had a clear <b>majority</b> in both Wales and Scotland.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Alex elected by large <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Despite the king's efforts, Newcastle and his followers won a substantial <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>narrow</COLLOC><COLLOC>slim</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The Conservatives were then returned with a narrow <b>majority</b> of 26, and Churchill became prime minister for the second time.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Although Royalists voted against the document, the Parliamentarians just managed to scrape home with a slim <b>majority</b> of 11 votes.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>reduced</COLLOC><COLLOC>increased</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Speaking after the election the Prime Minister said, "The British people wanted to return a Labour government but with a reduced <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>While free on appeal, Berger was elected to Congress in 1919 with an increased <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>overall</COLLOC><COLLOC>absolute</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>In fact, the Conservatives were 7.5 % ahead and John Major was able to form a Conservative government with an overall <b>majority</b> of 21 seats.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Bucking the national trend, the CSU won an absolute <b>majority</b> in the 1998 Bavarian state elections using the slogan,' Germany is not a country for immigrants. ' Stoiber mounted a vicious campaign against the dual nationality bill.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>simple</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>In the 15th South Korean National Assembly elections held on April 11 this year, the ruling NKP headed by President Kim Young-sam won 139 seats, 11 short of a simple <b>majority</b> in the 299-seat parliament.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>comfortable</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Durkan held on with a comfortable <b>majority</b> despite a 6.6 % increase in the Sinn Féin vote.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>parliamentary</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Last year Labour won a huge parliamentary <b>majority</b> on the basis of marginally more than 40 % of the popular vote.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>Labour</COLLOC><COLLOC>Tory</COLLOC><COLLOC>Sinn Fein</COLLOC><COLLOC>SDLP</COLLOC><ETC/></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>SDLP candidate Alex Attwood admitted his party had performed badly but remained upbeat in the face of the massive Sinn Fein <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This would translate into a Labour <b>majority</b> of 122, but in a hypothetical scenario with Mr Brown as Labour leader, the Party would sweep to power in another landslide with a majority of 234 (Independent, p.4, p.4 [analysis]).
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>two-thirds</COLLOC><COLLOC>60%</COLLOC><ETC/></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>They noted that, on 15 October 1986, the Provisionalshad come out in support of a policy of Sinn Féin memberstaking seats in the Dáil, and consequently, on 2 November, the SinnFéin Árd Fheis had voted by a two-third's <b>majority</b> to end its abstentionistpolicy vis -?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Thereafter the existing and proposed amended Bye-Laws are circulated to all corporate members in advance of an Extraordinary General Meeting (normally held in May on the same day as the Annual General Meeting) which has to approve them with a three-quarters <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>My model shows that her luck will run ou, and the Lib Dems will take a comfortable 5 % <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>government</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Nationalist councils: - 6 out of 6 councils with overall nationalist control share responsibility; - in 2 of these (Deny and Down) the SDLP are the <b>majority</b> party; - in Newry &amp; Moume the SDLP has half of the 30 seats; - in Magherafelt &amp; Limavady nationalists have a slim majority and the SDLP has to rely on either UUP or Sinn Fein for support; - in Omagh, where Sinn Fein is the largest party, the SDLP require the direct support of the UUP.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><DOMAIN label="pol"/></LabelGp><MEANING>in the US the amount by which the greater number of votes cast, as in an election, exceeds the total number of remaining votes</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>A fourth round of elections will be held to decide the winner between the leading two candidates in each constituency if neither obtains an absolute <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If no candidate wins an outright <b>majority</b>, a run-off election will be called.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The coalition has a large <b>majority</b> in the lower house but a narrow one in the upper house or Senate.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="pol"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a party or group that receives the most votes</MEANING><LINK>majority leader</LINK><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>party</COLLOC><COLLOC>group</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Nationalist councils: - 6 out of 6 councils with overall nationalist control share responsibility; - in 2 of these (Deny and Down) the SDLP are the <b>majority</b> party; - in Newry &amp; Moume the SDLP has half of the 30 seats; - in Magherafelt &amp; Limavady nationalists have a slim majority and the SDLP has to rely on either UUP or Sinn Fein for support; - in Omagh, where Sinn Fein is the largest party, the SDLP require the direct support of the UUP.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Leader of the <b>majority</b> group of the Town Council is automatically appointed as Leader of the Council, at the first meeting of the Standing Committees for the following Municipal Year.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="law"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the age at which someone is legally considered to be an adult</MEANING><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>the age of majority</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>The Committee expressed concern that the judiciary in Saudi Arabia have discretion to decide that a child has reached the age of <b>majority</b> before the age of eighteen.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>reach</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Claims may also be brought in respect of personal injuries done to children for three years after they reach their <b>majority</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="mil"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the rank or office of a major</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>He had left the army as a major, but the clerks in the Horse Guards had determined that his <b>majority</b> was only brevet rank , not regimental, and so he had been forced to accept a lieutenant's pension.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrBlk><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>be in the majority</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to constitute the larger part</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>While women were in the <b>majority</b> in this group, there was also a significant minority of men.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Die hard hand coders still exist, of course, and bespoke ecommerce sites are still in the <b>majority</b>, if only by a whisker.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There are no shortages of state schools where Muslim pupils are in <b>majority</b>, such schools may be designated as Muslim schools under the management and control of Muslim educational Trust or Charities.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt></PhrBlk><CpdBlk><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>majority leader</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="pol"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the person who organises the members of the political party which has the most people elected in the US senate or House of Representatives</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>But Senator Bill Frist of Tennessee, the <b>majority</b> leader , scuttled that bill, partly because of White House opposition to the amendment.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Telegraph 10th Oct 2006 Within hours of North Korea's proclaimed nuclear test yesterday Dennis Hastert, the Republican speaker in Congress, and John Boehner, the Republican <b>majority</b> leader on Capitol Hill, issued politically charged statements.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Senator Trent Lott, who will become the <b>majority</b> leader now that the Republicans have recaptured the Senate, said the successor must be someone who "has the confidence of the American people, the markets and both sides philosophically and politically.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>majority rule</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="pol"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a system of government in which every person can vote and the party with the most votes wins power</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Business people played an important role in South Africa's transition to <b>majority</b> rule.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Real freedom Replacing our monarch with a <b>majority</b> rule does not equal freedom.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Communists, who are bound to live. in a narrow circle of a few individuals, in which circle the petty struggles for dominion are the more acutely felt, ought decidedly to abandon the Utopias of elected committees ' management and majority rule; they must bend before the reality of practice which is at work for many hundreds of years in hundreds of thousands of village communities - the folkmoot - and they must remember that in these communities, <b>majority</b> rule and elected government have always been synonymous and concomitant with disintegration - never with consolidation.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt></CpdBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
