<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="100" proforma="ranks_titles"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>major</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><MEANING>important, serious, significant, big</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually attrib</CORPAT><ExCnt><EX>Neo Surrealist, Post Modern, Conceptual Lei has shown his work in international festivals and <b>major</b> world art galleries.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A <b>major</b> part of the course will focus on further developing the mathematical writing skills of the student through the device of a notebook.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Of <b>major</b> importance are: The European Directive on Data Protection.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Her coach said later that the injury was not <b>major</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We make all kinds of sacrifices in life, some which are <b>major</b>, but most are fairly trivial.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCorPattCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>place</COLLOCTYPE><CollocGp><COLLOC>city</COLLOC><COLLOC>road</COLLOC><COLLOC>route</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The activists used 172 buses to get to Marmara from Thessaloniki, the nearest <b>major</b> city.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Often there will be red and white signs to guide you from a <b>major</b> road.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Skipton lay at the junction therefore of two <b>major</b> routes.</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>problem</COLLOCTYPE><CollocGp><COLLOC>problem</COLLOC><COLLOC>issue</COLLOC><COLLOC>concern</COLLOC><COLLOC>obstacle</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Empty pesticide containers are a <b>major</b> problem for tobacco farmers in Brazil.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Paddy Gray, senior lecturer in Housing Management, said: Housing has become a <b>major</b> political issue on both sides of the border.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The perceived under-reporting of homophobic incidents is a <b>major</b> concern.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Problems encountered The negative attitude of the administrators proved to be a <b>major</b> obstacle to success.</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>event</COLLOCTYPE><CollocGp><COLLOC>event</COLLOC><COLLOC>change</COLLOC><COLLOC>breakthrough</COLLOC><COLLOC>development</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Formal Dinner Our final night in Kano was recognised by a formal dinner, which seemed to be a <b>major</b> event in the town.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There have been no <b>major</b> changes to the strategy. </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However, negotiations concluded for summer 2005 without a <b>major</b> breakthrough.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is a <b>major</b> development to be training people at community level to support families.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>influence</COLLOCTYPE><CollocGp><COLLOC>factor</COLLOC><COLLOC>source</COLLOC><COLLOC>impact</COLLOC><COLLOC>contribution</COLLOC><COLLOC>player</COLLOC><COLLOC>cause</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Raised cholesterol levels are a <b>major</b> risk factor for heart disease.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The main greenhouse gas which affects climate change is carbon dioxide, of which transport is a <b>major</b> source.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The development of the polymerase chain reaction has had a <b>major</b> impact on medicine.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The commitment of both groups to the project has made a <b>major</b> contribution to its progress.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>An independent Britain, by contrast, can be a <b>major</b> player on the world stage.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Work-related stress is a <b>major</b> cause of occupational ill health.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>surgery</COLLOCTYPE><CollocGp><COLLOC>surgery</COLLOC><COLLOC>operation</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Unfortunately by the end of 2001 she needed <b>major</b> surgery which left her very weak.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Canadian Wing cares for patients who have undergone <b>major</b> operations.</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>play a major part/role in sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Our preaching should be informed by issues affecting society in which technology plays a <b>major</b> part.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Course Coordinator will play the <b>major</b> role in pastoral care for students on the Wellcome Trust 4-year PhD programme.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="attr_only"/><MEANING>biggest, most important</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>CERN's current <b>major</b> development in particle physics is the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) [16], currently under construction.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Cornwall is a hotspot of marine mammal strandings in the UK with fisheries bycatch considered the <b>major</b> cause of mortality.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>major</b> source of discrimination identified by respondents was age, which was cited by 17 %.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The High Sheriff's Race Night, held annually at Leicester Racecourse in July, is Crimebeat's <b>major</b> fund-raising event.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Also I am not convinced that a lack of leadership at the national level is our <b>major</b> problem.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Singer remarks:' My <b>major</b> income has always been my academic salary.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><LabelGp><STYLE label="spok"/></LabelGp><MEANING>very serious, significant or noteworthy</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually predic</CORPAT><ExCnt><EX>For starters they forgot my remote keyboard - ok not <b>major</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>``It was <b>major</b>,'' said coach Chris Ford, whose team has dates with Utah and San Antonio before hitting the road.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It was pretty <b>major</b> . I could n't believe it when I saw police all over the place . </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" 1985 was a really <b>major</b> year. My father died and so I inherited his accountancy company , I was married in the Summer and soon after I was going to send my new book to print .</EX></ExCnt></FwkCorPattCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>nothing/something major</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>And a few more niggles and mix ups but nothing <b>major</b>.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If it wasn't anything <b>major</b> then why close off the whole high street?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Listen, sorry for calling on you at such short notice, but we're talking something <b>major</b> here.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="spor"/><META label="esp"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a well-known and important tournament or league</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually plural</CORPAT><ExCnt><EX>Playing competitive golf until 1973, he won 37 tournaments, including 7 <b>majors</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He never played in the <b>majors</b> but he is headed for the Pro Football Hall of Fame.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I haven't won any <b>majors</b>, haven't won any of the high-prestige tournaments.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Els, last season's US Open champion, led the last <b>major</b> of the year with a round to go.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCorPattCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="comm"/></LabelGp><MEANING>one of the biggest or best-known companies in a particular sphere</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually plural</CORPAT><ExCnt><EX>Venezuela car rental options are pretty limited and all the <b>majors</b> appear to offer the same poor service.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Japanese authorities have confirmed they are investigating allegations that ten record companies - including some of the <b>majors</b> - colluded to offer one mobile phone company favourable rates giving their mobile download service an unfair advantage.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They provide a valuable feed and also give the <b>majors</b> a presence in markets that would otherwise be non-viable for them to serve.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCorPattCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>In October 2005, after months of data analysis and discussion with all stakeholders - including the two soft drink <b>majors</b> - the standards were agreed by the committee.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>oil</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Our team has broad experience and knowledge of the oil industry, regularly advising oil <b>majors</b> and operators on all aspects of their business.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><META label="esp"/><REGION label="AmE"/><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a main subject of study at university</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>As one of my <b>majors</b> was Criminology, I have been involved in crime prevention plans for the harbour.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You can begin in a liberal arts program to receive a general education, before deciding on your <b>major</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is possible for a student to have two <b>majors</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They offer a number of MBA <b>majors</b> and minors and have outstanding Faculty in Negotiations, Finance, Marketing and Operations, with particularly exciting courses in Quality Management and Finance, since they are an accredited institution for GE's famous 6 Sigma programme.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>in</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Which could have been his lot after he graduated from the City University of New York in 1972 with a <b>major</b> in psychology.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is home to 180 full-time students from 13 countries offering a music degree with <b>majors</b> in performance (piano and orchestral instruments) and composition.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>So the school brought the faculty together to fill out its course roster, eliminate overlap and inaugurate a <b>major</b> in technology and e-commerce last fall.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a student studying a particular subject as their major</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>They were both political science <b>majors</b>, but Poppy says their first love was fashion.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Education students ' entrance exam scores are also lower, with about half as many education <b>majors</b> in the top quartile as humanities and social science majors.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Prerequisites : Normally biology or biochemistry majors only </EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="mus"/></LabelGp><MEANING>(of a scale) with intervals of a semitone between the third and fourth, and seventh and eighth notes</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually attrib</CORPAT><COMMENT>see examples</COMMENT></FwkCorPattCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>scale</COLLOC><COLLOC>key</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>One is the <b>major</b> scale , the other is the minor scale both derived from ancient modes.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>scales (there are many forms of these - including the basic 36 scales [ <b>major</b> and two forms of minor], plus chromatic - which can be played hands separately and together</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Beginning on the fourth note of the <b>major</b> key gives us the Lydian mode, which in the key of C major goes: F, G, A, B, C, D, E. </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Some secondary triads: II and VI in a <b>major</b> key and VI in a minor key.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="post_mod"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="mus"/></LabelGp><MEANING>based on the major scale of a particular note</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>An unusual change of key occurs: C <b>major</b>, Bb major, Bb minor, A major, B major, Ab major and A minor.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The G <b>major</b> scale has exactly the same notes as the C major scale, except that it has one note sharpened.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Again taking the scale of C <b>major</b> as a prototype we have: </EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>in A/B/C/D major</CHUNK><VarCnt><VAR>in the key of A/B/C/D major</VAR></VarCnt><ExCnt><EX>The ' cello starts the third movement with a lively polka-tempo melody; it provides the movement's dominant idea, against which are contrasted a series of varied ideas including a strong chordal subject first played in C major by the' cello, and a syncopated woodwind melody, returning in A <b>major</b>, the key in which the dance-like opening theme returns and in which the concerto ends exuberantly.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The recital concluded with Brahms Sonata in G <b>major</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It's written in the key of E <b>major</b>, and features a recurring phrase ("here I am ....
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><COMMENT>For PHASE 2B TRANSLATORS: the brief examples are formulaic and not from the corpus</COMMENT><POS code="n"/><VarCnt><VAR>Major</VAR></VarCnt><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="army"/></LabelGp><MEANING>an army rank above captain and below lieutenant colonel, or an officer of this rank</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Major Jones</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Major Jane Smith</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>yes, Major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>orders from the major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to have the rank of major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to promote sb to major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to be a major in the army</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><VarCnt><VAR>Major</VAR></VarCnt><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><DOMAIN label="airf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a rank in the US air force, above captain and below lieutenant colonel, or an officer of this rank</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Major Jones</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Major Jane Smith</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>yes, Major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>orders from the major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to have the rank of major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to promote sb to major</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to be a major in the air force </EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><VarCnt><VAR>Major</VAR></VarCnt><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="mil"/><DOMAIN label="mus"/></LabelGp><MEANING>an officer in charge of a section of a band</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE>instrument</COLLOCTYPE><CollocGp><COLLOC>drum</COLLOC><COLLOC>trumpet</COLLOC><COLLOC>pipe</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>My grandfather was a <b>drum major</b> in the Royal Berkshire Regiment.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Tuesday 7 Mar 06 At 0745 hrs on Tuesday morning, training parade band fall in with <b>Drum Major</b> Hill.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Hardys <b>trumpet major</b> gives up on the woman he loves in his brothers favour.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He had three sons who all became pipe <b>majors</b> in the Shotts and Dykehead Pipe Band.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrVBlk><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>major in</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><LabelGp><META label="esp"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to study something as a main subject</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Louisa trained with the New Zealand School of Dance from 1994 - 1996, <b>majoring</b> in contemporary dance.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It took another friend, (who <b>majored</b> in psychology) to help us unravel the mystery of the school's inconsistent attitude.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Industrial placements are compulsory for all those <b>majoring</b> in leisure management.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>major on</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><LabelGp><REGION label="non_AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to have a particular emphasis, to centre around something</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Despite his love of Thai food, Tolley has returned to classics for the menu at Plateau, <b>majoring</b> on rustic French.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The priorities of most companies developing GM crops have <b>majored</b> on western consumer foods whose main benefit is to the producer not the hungry.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Majoring</b> on the visual is vital in an environment where levels of literacy are often poor.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt></PhrVBlk><CpdBlk><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>major general</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><COMMENT>For PHASE 2B TRANSLATORS: the brief examples are formulaic and not from the corpus</COMMENT><POS code="n"/><VarCnt><VAR>Major General</VAR></VarCnt><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="army"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a very high army rank above bridgadier and below lieutenant general, or an officer of this rank</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Major General Jones</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Major General Jane Smith</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>yes, Major General</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>orders from the major general</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to have the rank of major general</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to promote sb to major general</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to be a major general in the army</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><VarCnt><VAR>Major General</VAR></VarCnt><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><DOMAIN label="airf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a very high rank in the US air force, above brigadier general and below lieutenant general, or an officer of this rank</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Major General Jones</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Major General Jane Smith</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>yes, Major General</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>orders from the major general</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to have the rank of major general</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to promote sb to major general</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>to be a major general in the air force </EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>major league</CPD><VarCnt><VAR>Major League</VAR></VarCnt></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="spor"/><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a professional league, especially of baseball teams, playing at the highest level</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually plural</CORPAT><ExCnt><EX>Jackie Robinson, US baseball player, the first black player in the <b>major leagues</b>, born in Cairo, Georgia (1972).
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Last season they were second in the <b>major leagues</b> with 167 steals.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Joey Jay, major league baseball player and the first Little Leaguer to reach the <b>major leagues</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCorPattCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>player</COLLOC><COLLOC>team</COLLOC><COLLOC>baseball</COLLOC><COLLOC>soccer</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>It was also a team where once-great <b>major league</b> players went to spend their remaining years in the sport.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He proved he belonged in the lineup of a <b>major league team</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>Major League</b> Baseball playoffs were winding ever closer to a dramatic finish, which I feared I would only read about online.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Savarese, 29, has played in Serie B in Italy as well as in <b>Major League</b> Soccer in the United States.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>major-league</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="pertnm"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="spor"/></LabelGp><MEANING>connected with the major leagues in US professional sport, especially baseball</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Furcal set the foundation for a six-run rally on the Reds bullpen with the fifth home run of his young <b>major-league</b> career.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Cole has 143 stolen bases in six <b>major-league</b> seasons.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Schott will not be involved in the day-to-day decisions required to run a <b>major-league</b> club, according to a MLB release.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="adj"/><GRAM code="attr_only"/><MEANING>important, leading or significant</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The confessions of supergrasses, or pentiti, from the 1984 case of Tommasso Buscetta to his Neapolitan counterpart, Pasquale Galasso, in 1993 brought to the surface realities which many had only guessed at, about the intimate ties between <b>major-league</b> gangsters and parts of the political establishment.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Q: Your work in KILL BILL has refocussed attention on you as a <b>major-league</b> sex symbol.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The US played a key role under President Clinton in bringing the IRA/SF ' in from the cold ', notably with the decision before the IRA ceasefire in 1994 to grant Gerry Adams a visaagainst State Department advice and in the teeth of British oppositionand the doors thus opened for the republicans not only to political power but to <b>major-league</b> fundraising.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt></CpdBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
