<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="10"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>majorette</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>a girl or woman in a marching band who twirls a baton</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The flag dance - it's in Act 2 - went without a hitch this time, though it reminded me irresistibly of baton-twirling <b>majorettes</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I am reminded of the comment from one of Holly's fellow <b>majorettes</b> that Holly is still dancing but now she is dancing in Heaven.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You can march like a <b>majorette</b> or a pipe band major or walk like a giant or a tiny mouse.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>drum</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>These crystals control the rate at which the machine works and keep everything in time, in, much the same way as the drum <b>majorette</b> tossing her baton in front of the Dagenham Girl Pipers keeps her band in time.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>"Being Beckham was great but I wasn't too pleased about the <b>majorette</b> costume.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>For more information: Email: tedwhealing@lwcdial.net Tel and Fax: +44 (0)23 9252 5931 Visit: www.centralband.com or write to: The Central Band of The Royal British Legion National Headquarters 48 Pall Mall London SW1Y 5JY Youth bands and majorette troupes The Royal British Legion has a number of youth bands and <b>majorette</b> troupes in England and Wales.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The housemates spent much of yesterday afternoon and this morning practicing the <b>majorette</b> routine they need to perform later today and are looking forward to proving themselves in their performance.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>majorettes</SUBFORM><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="pl_only"/><MEANING>a group for girls or women who march and twirl batons</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>When I was in <b>majorettes</b> and entered marching and baton twirling competitions we were all given numbers and called by those.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Annette Bening gives an impressive performance as his materially obsessed wife, who only gets excited when she is being screwed by a successful competitor and never with her own husband, who has to take solace wanking in the shower or lusting after the leader of his daughter's <b>majorettes</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>won't stop A: hmm huh huh Q: you A: ha ha ha sorry Q: ha ha ha ha yeah Q:okay [...] God...they're they're just like chalk and cheese then aren't they really A: yeah they are mm they're both very pretty girls very very pretty mm Holly's make up mm Jess playing with the boys you know football and things like that mm Holly Holly likes football as well she likes all that but she she doesn't she looks more girly and uh she likes her <b>majorettes</b> and things like that and Q: Do you think they kind of bring out you know bring out the best the best in each other really one gets the sort of the girly element from the other and the other gets the tomboyish element sort of A: probably yeah it's quite funny when Jess turned round and said I will be your bridesmaid and I will put a dress on I mean it was quite quite funny mm to see her say that because I've never seen her in a dress or a skirt or anything
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
