<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="120" time="1920"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>make</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to prepare food or drink</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Simply pausing to <b>make</b> a hot drink , or taking a few deep slow breaths can make a difference to your stress levels.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Then you can leave him to play or watch a video while you get on with <b>making</b> dinner .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>All our recipes use the' all-in-one' method for <b>making</b> cakes .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>I want to wrap her in a duvet, <b>make</b> her cups of tea.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I will ask Kara to <b>make</b> you a meal .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The first thing I do is feed my cat Carma, then <b>make</b> myself a cup of coffee to wake myself up.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>for</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>By the time I had walked the dog, <b>made</b> lunches for everybody and consumed so many litres of water, I was ready.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>My next job was to get up earlier than the regiment, put the kettles on and spend the day <b>making</b> drinks for 35 men.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I <b>made</b> a huge pasta salad for a bbq last year.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>from</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>We also offer our own white wine, which is <b>made</b> from the grapes grown in our vineyard.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>True mozzarella is <b>made</b> from the milk of the water buffalo imported from India to Campania in the 7th century.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>out of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>One day she was so hard up that she <b>made</b> a pudding out of goats milk.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>with</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>You can also <b>make</b> it with dried apricots which are full of calcium.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A better plan is to <b>make</b> a syrup with sugar and water in which apples are stewed whole or sliced.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>English Chefs serve up what can only be called oat pudding; <b>made</b> with flaked oats , milk, cream and sugar.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to create/produce sth new</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX><b>Make</b> your own model of the Solar System!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>200 years ago, everyone <b>made</b> their own clothes .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He still <b>makes</b> films at his ' Gorsewood ' home studio in the New Forest.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Have bought some thin dowel to <b>make</b> him a triple perch.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They're <b>making</b> me a costume for Guys and Dolls.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Mr. Osborn , the school 's woodwork master , <b>made</b> us a wooden holy water stoop to use in the school hall .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>for</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Haven't you got some relatives here in this village who might help you to <b>make</b> baskets for me ?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I do have all sorts of games specially <b>made</b> for blind children.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Up to now, I have <b>made</b> curtains for our bedroom, the front room and spare room, and blinds for the nursery and bathroom, plus a few cushion covers and seat covers for my family.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The band <b>made</b> an album for Dart records, released in early 1975.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>from</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>The kitchen furniture itself can be <b>made</b> from recycled materials.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Q: One-Wear's disposable underwear is <b>made</b> from 100 % Cotton.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>out of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>I like making things out of nothing, like sewing, <b>making</b> things out of metal, I'm more into the primitive side of things.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>with</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>You need blue and red glasses to see the anaglyphs . I <b>made</b> mine with cellophane glued onto a cardboard frame which I place over my ordinary glasses .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>To develop alphabetic knowledge, the children can: · Look for plastic letters in water. · <b>Make</b> letters with Playdoh. · Match letters to an alphabet strip  and don't forget to do it outside!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In the clerestory, windows SII, SIV, NII and NIV, also by Willement, are <b>made with</b> fragments of 15th century glass.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Part"/><STRTYPE>Part_loc</STRTYPE><ExCnt><EX>For many years this little lathe , <b>made</b> in Korea but designed and distributed by the Japanese Sakai Special Camera Mfg. Co. Ltd. , was sold under various names in different countries. </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However , the trade deficit has been getting worse in recent months , as British consumers buy more goods <b>made</b> overseas . </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Christmas was a different matter , at school we made paper chains to decorate the classroom and to take home , ( during the war we would <b>make</b> them at home out of newspaper ).</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Part_X"/><STRSTAT>up</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>I think if you <b>make up</b> some nice curtains or blinds for the windows, they could be rather homey.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Make up</b> a little salad-face man with radishes for eyes, cucumbers for ears, a cherry tomato for his nose, lettuce for hair.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I know what your on about mate,but I have n't seen any in shops for a long time ... . Perhaps a nice engineer bloke can <b>make</b> one up for you</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><LINK>make up</LINK></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to cause time or space to be available for sb/sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>for</STRSTAT><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>time</COLLOC><COLLOC>space</COLLOC><COLLOC>room</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>You need to <b>make</b> time for yourself , Archie . These exams are important but do n't let them be to the detriment of everying else in your life.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It was in April 1980 that the cinema building was finally demolished to <b>make room</b> for the Ring Road.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In the first stage the cervix, or neck of the womb, gradually opens up to <b>make space</b> for the baby.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Vinf_to"/><ExCnt><EX>However little time you have, <b>make time</b> to see these.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>During the summer term the paper versions of journals held electronically will move from the reading rooms to Wickford, <b>making</b> space to move the current parts of journals to the upper floors.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Firstly, you need to make sure that you <b>make</b> the time to actually carry out your action plan.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>By <b>making time</b>, pleasant tasks will not become chores - and once they have been adapted, they will in turn make time for secondary tasks.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to arrange bedcovers neatly after having slept in a bed</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>bed</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Don't forget to <b>make</b> the bed !
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The children help in small ways like <b>making</b> their own beds .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I get washed, clean my teeth, get dressed and <b>make</b> my bed .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to cause sth to be formed somewhere</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>dent</COLLOC><COLLOC>scratch</COLLOC><COLLOC>stain</COLLOC><COLLOC>mess</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The stone did not puncture the roof of the cage, but it <b>made</b> a dent about two inches deep.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>So the hard plastic brushes of a car wash will <b>make</b> scratches which will catch the light as seen in the photo above. this is often called spider-webs or cob-webs for obvious reasons.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Not much blood would have been needed to <b>make</b> the stains , so it would not have been obvious to anyone else if she had blood on her hands.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Epoxy will produce a better result in the right hands, but applied incorrectly will <b>make</b> a real mess .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Part"/><STRTYPE>Part_loc</STRTYPE><ExCnt><EX>The blood from the clown's wrists <b>made</b> a large pool on the floor, which stretched to the corner of the note that he had left for his wife.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>hole</COLLOC><COLLOC>mark</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>There was a table and chair in the middle of the room - clearly well used as the chair had <b>made</b> four holes in the carpet!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>'But you must have <b>made</b> a dreadful mark on your clean white frock.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>used with some nouns to show that sb performs the action associated with the noun</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>decision</COLLOC><COLLOC>change</COLLOC><COLLOC>effort</COLLOC><COLLOC>mistake</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Once a decision had been <b>made</b> the Committee would be informed.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There are many self-help life-coaching books which can help you think about how to <b>make</b> changes to your life.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Many people do not <b>make</b> any effort to introduce others to Jesus.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Ask if you don't understand and re-start an answer if you <b>make</b> a mistake.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>payment</COLLOC><COLLOC>choice</COLLOC><COLLOC>claim</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>At the Post Office You can <b>make</b> a payment at any Post Office using your rent payment card, which you will receive in the post.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Without this information, we can't <b>make</b> choices about the type of farming we wish to support.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In April 1999, he <b>made</b> a claim for disability discrimination.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>attempt</COLLOC><COLLOC>noise</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The teacher <b>made</b> no attempt to intervene in this.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If a child is running around <b>making</b> a lot of noise in the house the parent could become very angry and lose control.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>used with some nouns meaning to agree with sb about doing sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>pact</COLLOC><COLLOC>agreement</COLLOC><COLLOC>deal</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Last year I <b>made</b> a pact with my two older brothers that we should grow a beard for Christmas.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Make</b> an agreement about how long you can stay on and what you do there.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In an effort to convince his son to quit, Nick <b>makes</b> a deal with him that he finds very hard to keep.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to think up sth; to devise sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>rule</COLLOC><COLLOC>plan</COLLOC><COLLOC>policy</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>I don't <b>make</b> the rules , I just implement them.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I had an incident like that when I first started work, I was only sixteen, it went on for ages and |I was becoming increasingly frightened and nervous so I <b>made</b> a plan , I waited until he touched my leg under the packed canteen table AGAIN and I then stood up and screemed and shouted at him to keep his dirty old mans hands off me and never touch me again.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX> All staff involved in <b>making</b> policy for Wales are aware of the scheme.
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make the law</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Do judges <b>make the law</b> or do they find it?
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to call someone on the telephone</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>call</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>I <b>made</b> a telephone call complaining to the BBC.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There are ways to get round this: - Dialling 141 prior to <b>making</b> a call to withhold your number although it may still appear on your phone bill .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The headset also can be used with Logitech's award-winning QuickCam Web cameras to <b>make</b> video calls on the PC.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to arrange or organize sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>arrangement</COLLOC><COLLOC>date</COLLOC><COLLOC>appointment</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The Respondents visited the Home on 9th April 1992 in order to ascertain what arrangements had been <b>made</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They kissed, briefly, and <b>made</b> a date for about eleven the same morning, to see Karen onto the ferry.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Ask your doctor or practice nurse for any further information or to <b>make</b> an appointment .
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make plans</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>They had <b>made</b> plans to travel to Western Australia, Antarctica, Alaska and Hawaii, when Vyanine was knocked down by an electioneering-van in the Rue des Oiseaux.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to earn or get money</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>He has many plans for the future , one of which includes <b>making</b> a million euro !
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He <b>made</b> a large personal fortune, partly from fees, partly from shrewd investments.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You must not lose sight of your main object, which is to <b>make</b> money.</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make a living</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>I feel very lucky to be able to <b>make</b> a living doing what I do.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make a profit</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>For example, a retailer may decide not to <b>make</b> a profit on an item.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>used with some nouns to show that sb says sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>statement</COLLOC><COLLOC>comment</COLLOC><COLLOC>complaint</COLLOC><COLLOC>suggestion</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Mrs H sucked in a deep breath; she was about to <b>make</b> a statement.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The above comments were <b>made</b> by the publishers about what they are learning from the process of innovation.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Complaints and Compliments How to give compliments and <b>make</b> complaints about schools and their staff.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They critically reviewed each other's work, <b>making</b> suggestions for improvement.
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make a point</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>The Minister was about to <b>make</b> a point about regeneration.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to cause sb/sth to do sth/be in a particular state</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Vinf"/><ExCnt><EX>I'm looking for a sweet, caring gal who can <b>make</b> me laugh .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The nutrients in the banana skin are supposed to <b>make</b> the cabbages grow quickly.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We need to inspire, generate team spirit and <b>make</b> all staff feel special.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I gave the photo an antique finish to <b>make</b> it look more period.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP AJP"/><ExCnt><EX>The new user interface <b>makes</b> it easy to operate.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Well done girls, you have <b>made</b> an old manager very happy.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>During work to <b>make</b> the vessel safe, a decomposition reaction occurred, leading to an explosion in the vessel.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>She decides to <b>make</b> him jealous by finding another victim to show her feelings to.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make doing sth easier</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Planning ahead can <b>make</b> choosing a programme easier .
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it easier to do sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Here are some clues to <b>make it easier to</b> choose the right practitioner.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it easier for sb to do sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Unfortunately some people are using their mobiles and the internet to annoy and frighten others . This has become known as cyber bullying . Most young people say that when they are online or texting they are alone . This <b>makes it easier for</b> bullies to upset their victims as there are no adults around to interfere .</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it clear (that)</CHUNK><VarCnt><VAR>make it obvious (that)</VAR><VAR>make it plain (that)</VAR></VarCnt><ExCnt><EX>He <b>made</b> it clear that he did not want any help.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Circular <b>makes</b> it plain there is a need to have a clear audit trail between the contributions made and the infrastructure provided.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it known (that)</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>If you <b>make</b> it known that your mind can be changed he will attempt to change it for you.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to do sth so that sb/sth becomes sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Yvonne is picked up by a talent spotter who promises to <b>make</b> her a star.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Almost a year later and after a great amount of input to get the historical content correct, the show went ahead and as it was our first attempt at a performance in front of 8000 people we feel that our efforts helped <b>make</b> the show a success.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Thank you to everyone for <b>making</b> it such a memorable day.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Team, which is based both at the Cheltenham and Gloucester offices, has doubled the number of its personnel in the last two years <b>making</b> it one of the largest independent Corporate Finance Teams in the region.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>into</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>But the media (and the public) have <b>made</b> her into a saint.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Corrie wrote down her story in a book called The Hiding Place, which was later <b>made</b> into a film of the same name.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The fruit, with plenty of sugar, can be bottled, stewed or <b>made</b> into jam.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>His saturnine spirit appealed to younger bohemians who were anxious to <b>make</b> idols of an earlier generation's tormented souls, but even so, it cannot have been easy for Rothko always to be the pessimist among the optimists.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A great scholar, numbered among the ' Doctors of the Church ', he was also a' boney fetcher' and <b>made</b> enemies even of friends.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make a success of sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>They perform for corporate events, weddings, balls and parties and are dedicated to <b>making a success of</b> any event.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to give sb a particular position or responsibility</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>They also <b>made</b> her husband commander in chief of a Dutch army unit with full authority.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Henry <b>made</b> himself head of the Church of England.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I was <b>made</b> senior master and development director to manage changes to new buildings.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP AJP"/><ExCnt><EX>For many generations the territory had been divided into three divisions politically and these were preserved as administrative districts, each under a native governor who was <b>made</b> responsible for the welfare and good order of the people of his district.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to mean that sb/sth is sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Just having an English number plate still does not <b>make</b> me a Brit, does it?</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The tower of St Bene't 's is Saxon , which <b>makes</b> it the oldest building in Cambridge .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Being brought up in a christian home is n't enough to <b>make </b> you a christian .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP AJP"/><ExCnt><EX>I cannot freely move to the US and work there because they impose limits on immigration . I dont feel that makes them <b>racist</b> towards me.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Lawyers using the approach argue that , just because a defendant committed some wrongs , that does not <b>make </b> him guilty of more serious crimes , like murder .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We 've never made the effort because people in most countries make the effort to learn English . And that saves us a job . Which doesn't <b>make</b> it right .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to have the right qualities for sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>More popular with the public than with his party , Mr Rocard would<b>make</b> a strong Socialist candidate for president .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The play is very compelling - it would <b>make</b> a riveting hour on TV.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You're going to <b>make</b> someone a fantastic husband.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to equal a particular amount</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>How many nines , or nine of how many <b>make</b> twenty seven .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to decide that sth gives a particular total/time when calculating an amount/measuring sth/looking at your watch </MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>15million people out of a population of 60 million ... . I <b>make</b> that about 65 % </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In this case <b>I made it</b> 30mm long which left a minimum of 10mm from the top which was an ideal size of paraffin block.
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>what time do you make it?</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>" "What <b>time do you make it</b>? "4.59," said Des. </EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to force or persuade sb to do sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Vinf"/><ExCnt><EX>All the local street traders tried to <b>make</b> us buy something.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>She describes how her news editor repeatedly tried to <b>make</b> her sit on his lap.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Faith hates being <b>made</b> to do chores by Cynthia.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>I refuse to answer any more questions and you can't <b>make</b> me.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You can come quietly or I can <b>make</b> you.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If the child doesn't want to do it I think it's wrong to <b>make</b> her.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to cause sth to be successful</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The friendly welcome and ski guiding were what really <b>made</b> the holiday.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The actors did a great job of keeping the evening going and reallly<b>made</b> the night.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They knew how to do things then . " The mantelpiece <b>makes</b> the room . It 's inset with lovely antique orange tiles . </EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make sb's day</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX><b>Make her day</b> with a gift of beautiful diamond studs.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>for</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>So I did my speech and I hope that I pulled it off . But what really <b>made</b> it for me was when Tony Benn came up to me and said it was a good speech .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As soon as we were told what we would be doing , I loved the thought of the challenge . It <b>made</b> it for me even more when I was asked to help , by staying half way up to assist anyone with their route </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Thank you so much for all your trouble in getting it to us today on his birthday - it was more than we could have hoped for . It has <b>made</b> the day for us all.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to succeed in arriving somewhere after a long hard journey or in time for sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>We just <b>made</b> the border in time and praising our own luck carried along the road to Dawson.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The ferry was an hour and a half late and we <b>made</b> our flight with ten minutes to spare.</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>On weekdays, however, Sue is prepared to stay open for a customer who can't <b>make it</b> by 4.30 pm provided they call to let her know they are coming!</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Some Crusaders would never <b>make it to</b> the Holy Land; some would never return home.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>She was quite scared as she was shaking . Still we all <b>made it</b> home in one piece .</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to be able to attend an event</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>If you can't <b>make</b> the meeting but would like to know more, please contact Tommy for further details.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The afternoon was planned as a rehearsal for the firemen but unfortunately Johnny wasn't able to <b>make</b> the session due to work commitments.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Some people feel a sense of guilt when a guest comments, "I won't be able to <b>make</b> your wedding, but where are you registered?</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>If you can <b>make it</b>, would be nice to meet up.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I hope I'll be able to <b>make it </b> to your show in Toronto.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to succeed in achieving a sth/reaching the required level or standard</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The target was to <b>make </b>the top four . We have achieved being in the top six </EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>target</COLLOC><COLLOC>deadline</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>People tend to relax if they are ahead of budget or have <b>made</b> their target.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Licensing Minister admitted this week that only about two thirds of license holders will <b>make</b> the deadline .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>rank</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Toni worked her way through the ranks becoming the first girl to <b>make</b> the rank of Band Sergeant Major.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>The show became a worldwide phenomenon and David had finally <b>made it</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Please get as many sponsors as you can and we will be able to <b>make it</b> to the finals!</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it big</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>He is an ambitious man who aspires to <b>make it big</b> some day.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to succeed in being included in sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The more reasons you can give, the more chances you'll have of <b>making</b> the list.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" A new film profiling May Gurney people at work and showing the company's values in action was well received - including a selection of amusing' outtakes' that didn't <b>make</b> the final film.</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>headlines</COLLOC><COLLOC>papers</COLLOC><COLLOC>news</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Children and young people are always <b>making</b> the headlines  often for the wrong reasons.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>His death didn't <b>make</b> the papers, until now.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Here 's your chance to <b>make</b> the news ! Every company has a story to tell . Why not tell yours to the world ?</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>charts</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>He released a number of singles and a couple of them <b>made</b> the charts.</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>into</STRSTAT><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it into sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>There will be at least 100 fly tiers from around the world - possibly enough to <b>make it into</b> the Guinness Book of Records.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Some of these terms may <b>make it into</b> dictionaries, others won't.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Tesco.com was the only grocery etailer to <b>make it into the</b> recently published Interactive Media in Retail Group's top 20 Internet list.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to succeed in getting into a team</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>I'll be training really hard to make sure I <b>make</b> the team for the London Olympics.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Mark Regan also <b>makes</b> the squad despite not taking to the field in the victory over the Barbarians.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>into</STRSTAT><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it into sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>He played for the reserves, never quite <b>made it into</b> the first team .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Both players missed out on training today and Royle will wait until Friday to see if they will <b>make it into</b> his 16 man squad .
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to not die as a result of an illness or accident</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>`Right lung's collapsed -- he'll need a chest drain if he <b>makes it</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It was the worst experience in my life of course, but there were babies in there in worse shape than mine, so I bit my lip and endured, I knew she would <b>make it</b> and be fine.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>through</STRSTAT><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it through sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>October 11, 2004 at 09:44 PM EDT Christa called at 7:40 to report that Nate <b>made it through</b> surgery.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Had I waited much longer to go in, I may not have <b>made it through</b> the morning.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Thankfully, he <b>made it through</b> the war, later rising to the rank of Admiral.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><LabelGp><META label="usu"/><REGION label="AmE"/><STYLE label="spok"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to pretend to be, to do or to know sth or that sth is true</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>like</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Salsa music and dance are very important to the Cubans, so <b>make</b> like the natives and learn to salsa.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Make</b> like a Rabbit . Before you nibble a bit of your lunch , take out a bag of carrots and some low-calorie salad dressing .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>All I had to do was <b>make like a</b> patient in a sanatorium.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make like one is doing sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>She <b>made</b> like she was holding a gun.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I said: 'Y'know, you can get up there and do this poetry reading and <b>make</b> like you're a rock star - or you can actually be a rock star.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make like one feels sorry for sb</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>You want me to <b>make like</b> I feel sorry for them?
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make like it is the 1880s</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Well, you could <b>make like</b> it was the 1880's and sit around and wait (and wait) for him to ask YOU out OR you could do the girl power thing and ask him out yourself.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make as if to do sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Robert got up and, muttering something about marking, <b>made as if to</b> leave.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The girl ran over to the window and <b>made as if to</b> step out.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Neeson began the actual violence, headbutting the defendant once and <b>making as if to</b> do so again.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>a brand</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>They have over 3,000 cars in group stock, and supply all popular <b>makes</b> and models including: Ford, Vauxhall, Peugeot and Renault.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>An example being my wife who wanted a new mobile phone for Xmas and having found the exact <b>make</b>, model and colour on Amazon, I ordered it in early November.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Brenderup sides are approximately 10cm higher than any other <b>makes</b>, which improves the use of the trailer.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Perhaps he thought a mantra was a <b>make</b> of car.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>These type-faces encouraged customers to buy a particular <b>make</b> of machine.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The historic encounter was recorded for all time in photos of soldiers from both sides embracing each other and comparing notes on their respective <b>makes</b> of submachine gun.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="elec"/></LabelGp><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to close a circuit</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>To <b>make</b> a circuit , these components are connected together with metal connecting wires.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrBlk><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>be made of money</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to not have a lot of money - used esp when sb has asked you for money</MEANING><FwkCorPattCnt><CORPAT>usually in negatives </CORPAT><ExCnt><EX>Des , you must help him out ! " " You must be joking , I 'm not <b>made of money</b> ! " said Des . " I 've got hardly any left since I donated it all to you in order that you could get satellite television ! "</EX></ExCnt></FwkCorPattCnt><ExCnt><EX>As it is I'm s eriously considering hitch-hiking around the South Island, a number of the others at the hostel have done it and seem to think I'd be mad to pay coach fares unless I'm <b>made of money</b>, which I'm not.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>What kind of a careless brat were you, how was she supposed to wash melted tar out, did you think clothes grew on trees, was she <b>made of money</b>, was that the thanks she got for slaving day and night, wait till she told your father ...
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>be made for sb/sth</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>be perfectly suited for</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Lovely guitar. Knew it was <b>made for</b> me as soon as I tried it. </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Herb Robert was taken with the coated 2", and on the right is the same flower's sepal hairs shown up against dark backdrop using 1" lens, which incidentally fits directly over the camera's tiny lens barrel as if it were <b>made for</b> this job!</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The cattle are of the Hereford kind , and the sheep surpassing any animals of the kind that I ever saw . The animals seem to be <b>made for</b> the soil , and the soil for them .</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>be made for each other</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>But she still signs the contract and tells them they should think about marriage; they were <b>made for each other</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>it makes a change</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>used for saying that sth is different from and better than usual</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Some of the secondary school children only go to school to get the free lunch. <b>It makes a change</b> from nothing or take-away at home.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>It makes a change</b> to see somewhere like this being preserved, rather than being bulldozed to make way for more identikit modern housing schemes.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Working with others is good for mutual support and sharing ideas and it <b>makes a change</b> from working by yourself.</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make a day/night/weekend of it</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to spend a whole day/night/weekend on an activity, making it an occasion rather than just sth you do then go home </MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Mr Roden added: âIf youâd like to come and show your support, come down to Eden and <b>make a</b> day of it .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Woodstock Road eaterie just feels special, the sort of place where you want to dress up and <b>make a</b> night of it .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We decided to <b>make a</b> weekend of it and go up on the Saturday, the run itself being on the Sunday.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make a difference</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to do something that improves a situation</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>This is more than a garnish - it <b>makes</b> a huge difference to the dish.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Bradford Calderdale Kirklees Leeds Wakefield Adviser services Our experienced advisers can <b>make</b> a big difference to your business.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The key issue here is that I genuinely believe I am <b>making</b> a difference by being vegetarian.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make do</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to manage to make something sufficient even though it is ismall in quanitity, poor in quality etc</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>It concluded: "Many teachers do not have a realistic understanding of how much needs to be spent on books, perhaps because persistent underspending and a natural desire to do the best for students have encouraged them to improvise, <b>make do</b> or simply do without.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Apologies for the photo, it was a last minute encounter so had to <b>make do</b> with a camera phone.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>ONE OF the largest villages in the Horsham District is Southwater (population 10,000) whose residents have had to <b>make do</b> without a proper village centre for many generations.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make do and mend</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to live frugally, making use of what you have rather than buying new</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>So people didn't have to buy new clothes all the time, they were told to <b>make do and mend</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As a teacher in a state school I grew to expect poor pay , poor buildings , leaking roofs , cracked windows , inadequate resources . I expected to ' <b>make do and mend</b></EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I was raised in a dysfunctional family whose <b>make do and mend</b> war ethics influenced my childhood.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make it up to sb</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to do sth to make sb feel better after you did sth bad you did to them</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>I promised myself I would <b>make it up to</b> him somehow.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The goats are not so co-operative but then they have had to have their feet trimmed again . The animal care team always try and <b>make it up to</b> them by cutting some tasty brambles for them </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Sting has told reporters he is " disappointed and frustrated " that a throat infection has forced him to cancel the first three shows of his UK tour - including the opening night in home town Newcastle . But he has promised to <b>make it up to</b> his fans .</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make it with sb</PHR><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to have sex with sb</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Now, as in the past, Sex rears its perpetual head and the problem is how to <b>make it with</b> the chick in the front row.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It was rather extraordinary how he couldn't resist trying to <b>make it with</b> all his leading ladies. </EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make little of sth</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to not give sth much importance</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Parts of the press and television, some still government-controlled, have been energetically <b>making little of</b> the latest setback.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Dunlop's obituary 19 <b>makes little of</b> his involvement with the newspaper.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He told his parents about it , but <b>made little of</b> it and went to bed . During the night he died from ' delayed shock ' </EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make the most of sth</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to get maximum possible advantage, enjoyment etc out of sth</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>After all you only get one life - so <b>make the most of</b> it.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>To <b>make the most of</b> your Sherpa holiday it is essential that you choose a trek which is well within your capabilities.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>... way to <b>make the most of</b> your savings with us is by putting them in a smile cash mini ISA.</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make much of sth</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to give a lot of importance to sth</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Even today, local people <b>make much of</b> their association with Ireland.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The curriculum of the school <b>made much of</b> "The Three Rs" together with a considerable amount of learning poetry by heart.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>On your marks: Compared with other countries in the world, England doesn't really <b>make much of</b> its patron saint!
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>do you want to make something of it?</PHR><LabelGp><STYLE label="spok"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>do you want to fight/argue about sth?</MEANING><ExCnt><EX> ` You want to <b>make something of it </b>, do you ? ' ` No need to get touchy with me , mate . </EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make one's way</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to start moving towards somewhere</MEANING><ExCnt><EX><b>Make your way</b> steadily south, heading for the far southwest corner.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Outside in the corridor, a now free Larry is <b>making his way</b> to the Computer Room.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>From James's collection we <b>made our way</b> to the collection of Alan Archer.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to make progress in sth</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Just another guy <b>making his way</b> in the world.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As we <b>make our way</b> through everyday life, data is collected from each and every one of us.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Hamilton went on to <b>make her way</b> in café society.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>make way for sb/sth</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to move to one side so that sb/sth can pass</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Herald: Make way, <b>make way</b> for the great King David of Israel.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" Tik-Tok rose and walked over to the throne, all the Kings and Queens <b>making way</b> for him.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Shortly after two o'clock that afternoon the RUC cleared Divis Street to <b>make way</b> for an armoured car .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to be replaced by sb/sth</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The north west corner of the lock, around the tail gates, was demolished to <b>make way</b> for part of the Sports Centre.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>M&amp;S claims the reductions are normal practice to reduce winter stock and <b>make way</b> for the new spring lines.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We don't know how long Tony will wait before vacating Downing Street to <b>make way</b> for Gordon.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>on the make</PHR><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>trying to get an advantage for yourself out of a situation, especially dishonestly</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Yet the benefits system treats these people like fraudsters, assuming that anyone claiming benefits is <b>on the make</b>.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If you ask me , that lawyer of his is <b>on the make</b> . The cheek of it , charging £ 700 for drafting a simple power of attorney... work that in all probability wo n't take him more than half an hour to complete .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Kinnock does, he says, take very seriously what is now a really substantial and incessant attack on politics as an activity of remote, entirely self-interested, arrogant gits to the point where only a crank or somebody <b>on the make</b> would even join a political party.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>trying to attract sb in order to have a sexual relationship with the,</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>There's no real plot to this messy, incoherent comedy about four young black blokes <b>on the make</b> in London.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The title of the book he wrote about it , The Tomcat Chronicles , is fully descriptive . Yet he was far more than a gay man <b>on the make</b> . He was a gay pioneer who argued that homosexuality was not a disease</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>' There are few more impressive sights in the world than a Scotsman <b>on the make</b> ' (J.M.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>put the make on sb</PHR><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to try to make sb have sex with you</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Neither Republican nor Democrat has succeeded in policing members who gobble up contributions from political action committees, take sizable honoraria, lobby Congress after they've left office and wrap a cloak of secrecy around naughty senators who've been <b>putting the make on</b> women.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In "Under the Cherry Moon "he's playing a down-on-his-heels piano player on the French Riviera who crashes a party and <b>puts the make on</b> a French heiress.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Playing a sexed-up younger couple who jointly <b>put the make on</b> Loren, Daniel Pino and Megan Dodds have energy to burn in roles that hardly warrant it.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt></PhrBlk><PhrVBlk><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make after</PHRV><LabelGp><TIME label="dat"/></LabelGp></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to chase or follow sb</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Of course, she could have got out, <b>made after</b> him, had a scene.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Thwarted for a second time Bjorgussen <b>made after</b> his compatriots to the safer haven of Bodir Dur to winter and only in the spring did the full extent of his folly become apparent.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make at</PHRV><LabelGp><STYLE label="lit"/></LabelGp></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to attack sb</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Then did CHRISTIAN draw, for he saw it was time to stir him; and APOLLYON as fast <b>made at</b> him, throwing darts as thick as hail; by the which, notwithstanding all that CHRISTIAN could do to avoid it, APOLLYON wounded him in his head, his hand, and foot.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>with</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Very much surprised was he when I <b>made at</b> him with the rope's end and cursed him for a little blood-thirsty imp.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>For when the wel-affected Party began to assemble themselves together, for the appeasing of these tumultuous Villians, some of them <b>made at</b> them with their Clubs.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He forsook the sire and <b>made at</b> the son with his great compass-like legs, covering the ground in tremendous as well as rapid strides.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make away with</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv_prep"/><MEANING>to steal sth and take it away</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The robber then <b>made away with</b> approximately E500.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We had first made an examination of the kitchen, and especially of the kitchen fire, to see whether she might have <b>made away with</b> the papers during the instant that she was alone.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You cannot allow Araminta to <b>make away with</b> all your inheritance, Benedict.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make for</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to move towards sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>I ignore his churlish attitude and <b>make for</b> the bar.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>By nine o'clock in the evening, the wind had strengthened to near hurricane force, and the vessel was spotted in difficulties inside the Bass, her sails had given-way and the crew had no choice but to <b>make for</b> the shore.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Make for</b> the hills with a picnic and stumble upon hidden treasures as you wander through olive groves and terracotta-roofed hamlets.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to move towards sb as though you are going to attack them</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The dog <b>made for</b> him.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Once more on another night , opening his eyes he saw this strange unearthly visitor . Quickly he jumped out of bed and <b>made for</b> it - his hands in front of his face in the attitude of a boxer .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to result in sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>This <b>makes for</b> a role which ensures there is never a dull moment!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It <b>made for</b> an interesting induction into the online gaming environment.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The synergy between textile crafts and the historic cotton mill <b>make for</b> an ideal partnership!
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make of</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to use chances and opportunities in order to be successul</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The year is what you <b>make</b> of it.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>You've got your life ahead of you, and you've the chance to <b>make</b> something of it now that you've arrested your gambling problem.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Forest won an increasing share of possession the longer the second half went on . They <b>made</b> little of it at first , apart for a 20 yard shot from midfielder Sammy Clingan that flashed narrowly over the crossbar .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to understand the meaning or character of sb/sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP NP"/><ExCnt><EX>What do you <b>make</b> of it, Watson?</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Hitler had studied all the reports, including one submitted by the Forschungsamt, on this puzzling Moscow scene, and he wondered what to <b>make</b> of it.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>"What have you <b>made</b> of the team's performances?
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make off</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to run away</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="_0"/><ExCnt><EX>The men made off through the rear door of the premises into Downshire Parade where they <b>made off</b> on a motorcycle.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The car <b>made off</b> with the victim still in the boot, stopping on the Shore Road close to the Fortwilliam roundabout.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Pc Harman was on an Automatic Numberplate Recognition system (ANPR) operation when a vehicle approaching the ANPR site did a U-turn and <b>made off</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="Part"/><STRTYPE>Part_dir</STRTYPE><ExCnt><EX>They then <b>made off</b> down an alleyway.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The blue coloured car then <b>made off</b> towards the Barras.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The men <b>made off</b> through the rear door of the premises into Downshire Parade where they made off on a motorcycle.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>with</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>They forced the householder to the ground and <b>made off</b> with money and alcohol.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The intruder searched drawers in the house, and <b>made off</b> with a number of items, which included a wallet containing a sum of money.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It's not unknown for thieves to push a long pole through the letterbox, snatch the bunch of keys off the hook, then use them to <b>make off</b> with a vehicle.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make out</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to be able to see or hear sb/sth with difficulty</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>She was nearly three miles distant and though I had good long sight, I could barely <b>make her out</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Page 30: I have now <b>made out</b> the' illegible' word in Mr Ross's report on AMT's handwriting.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The singing filled the church, but, as ever, I could still <b>make out</b> my Mum's voice despite her thinking that she'd be too emotional to sing.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The edge of the towpath can be <b>made out</b> under the bridge.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="wh"/><ExCnt><EX>It was like surfing it was difficult to even <b>make out where</b> the track went the rain was so bad, never mind look for puddles and lines.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I couldn't really <b>make out what</b> she was saying but it sounded a bit like "King Star, King Star!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>She nearly caused herself an injury at her own front door, craning her neck to <b>make out who</b> was in the car with me.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to understand sth; to work sth out</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Nature is full of mystery; and we are here to <b>make out</b> the mysteries of Nature and draw them into day-light, not to cultivate and keep veiled the mysteries made by man in the day of his need or the night of his past.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He is not present in person to help us in <b>making</b> out his meaning .
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>as far as sb can make out</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>As far as I can <b>make out</b>, they had the following children: Sara Best born/baptised 17 Jan 1779 Richard Best born/baptised 19 Nov 1780 Mary Best born/baptised 20 July 1783 John Best born/baptised about 1784.</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="if"/><ExCnt><EX>We can't <b>make out if</b> its an official leak, though Aussie website Undercover say it was brought to their attention by the band's publicist, so presumably it is endorsed.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In fact they couldn't <b>make out if</b> she was a man or a woman because she always wore a man's cap, plusfours and leggings and had a voice like a rusty razor blade.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I could not <b>make out whether</b> his conscience was troubling him or whether he didn't realise what he was telling me.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="wh"/><ExCnt><EX>At Brigade HQ we were sitting down to tea and could not <b>make out</b> why our eyes were smarting so.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is not easy to <b>make out what</b> the excrescence on the west side of the Market Hall in the plan was intended to represent.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Yet even the disciples found it hard to <b>make out who</b> Jesus really was and still surprisingly little is known about him generally.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to understand sb's character</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The rector's wife was a bit of a mystery, and Betty couldn't really <b>make her out</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He seemed a nice enough fellow . I could never quite <b>make him out</b> .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to write the necessary information on a document of some kind</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The Doctor will consider the request and either <b>make out</b> a prescription or ask to see you.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Make out</b> a check list of things to do' as the great day approaches and make sure the bride has not forgotten anything vital Be there for your friend.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Exhibitors will be responsible for the placing of these cards and must satisfy themselves that the particulars on the card are correct. Cards are <b>made out</b> but exhibitors must complete UK Division and Class on both sides of the cards.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>to</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Invoices can be sent for multiple orders, but for single copies a cheque is required, <b>made out</b> to Manchester City Council.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Please <b>make</b> the Postal Orders out to Jason Shankey Limited.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to make people believe that sb is the specified type of person</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP Vinf_to"/><ExCnt><EX>I think the absolute Beginners forum was a good idea but i would drop the absolute part as some may feel it <b>makes them out to be</b> stupid.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Whatever he was, he was not the coward I had <b>made him out to</b> be.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>This phone was <b>made out</b> to be so good when it first came out they said the camera was very good quality, but in fact it is absolute rubbish.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to pretend that sth is true</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="that_0"/><ExCnt><EX>He believed in speaking the truth and did not try to <b>make out</b> we were better then we really were.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I <b>made out</b> that I did not know what they were saying.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>not as X as sb makes out</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Apparently Tim's not as experienced as he <b>made out</b> - it was all a show because he knew Siobhán needed the relaxation and he didn't want his nerves to put her off.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to put sth together</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>There are some days when I can't do anything, but I try to <b>make out</b> a "plan" for the week and score off everything I manage to do and it makes me feel great when I see even some of them ticked off!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It is obviously Nelson Goodman's conviction that both can <b>make out</b> an equally good case, which has led him to his relativist conclusion.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Firstly my wife Jay <b>made out a</b> begging e-mail which we sent to companies asking for their help or support to get us started, we soon started getting replies back with offers of help, for which we will always be greatful for.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to progress in a particular way</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="AVP"/><ExCnt><EX>The Swiss are diverse linguistically, but not socially, and they seem to <b>make out</b> pretty well without recourse to the police state.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In most respects I <b>made out</b> alright , with the understanding that things have a way of working out no matter how hard we plan and worry.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>7. How are you <b>making out</b> in graduate school?
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><REGIST label="inf"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to have sex, or kiss and touch in a sexual way</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="_0"/><ExCnt><EX>There is also a scene where four local teens sneak into what they believe is still a deserted house to <b>make out</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Meanwhile a bird hunter turns his rifle on a pair of afternoon lovers, <b>making out</b> in a nearby field.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>`` but we never dated or anything . '' `` No , '' Stiller agrees tentatively . `` We just _ . '' `` We <b>made out </b>a few times in the early days , '' Garofalo says .</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>with</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>His cameo, <b>making out with</b> a beautiful blonde bimbo (naturally!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Listening to her <b>make out with</b> a boy was wrong.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Stacy got drunk and <b>made out</b> with one of them.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make over</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to change the image of sb/sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>10 Years Younger: Winter Bikini Beach Special 1 x 60 minutes on Channel 4 Nicky Hambleton-Jones returns to <b>make over</b> one special bikini clad beach babe.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I'm not sure he can entirely convince at this point in his career as an ordinary man  <b>making him over</b> to look a bit like Bob Monkhouse doesn't quite cut it .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Home staging - <b>making over</b> your house cheaply for a sale - is big business, says Lucy Allen Wall Street Journal, Europe, October 2003</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to transfer legal ownership of sth to sb</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP PP_X"/><STRSTAT>to</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>`Marius Steen <b>made over</b> his three houses and about 75 per cent of his other assets to his son some years ago.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He then generally obliged the heirs and entrusted to them that they should give and <b>make over</b> to each person whatever he had left them.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Those who stayed on board until Hull then made the journey across country to Stonyhurst , a remote , though impressive , house in Lancashire begun in 1592 and in 1794 the unoccupied property of Thomas Weld , a former pupil of the English Jesuits . He made it over to them , together with the lands attached . </EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make towards</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_prep"/><MEANING>to go in the direction of sb/sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The Magma Member <b>made towards</b> the back of the enormous control room.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Without another word, Bert Rafferty gently picked up the frightened child and <b>made towards</b> the cliff.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Trudy threw a tantrum and <b>made towards her</b> with one arm raised, poised to strike.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make up</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to invent sb/sth new in one's mind</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>You could grab some terms from The Philosopher's Lexicon or maybe simply <b>make</b> them up!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I have read all the Chrestomanci books (what a marvellous character - I wish I could have <b>made</b> him up) and quite a few others, although this site has made me realise I have many more to go.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Debbie won't let me write speeches in advance ' cos she says I am funnier when I <b>make</b> it up on the night.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>story</COLLOC><COLLOC>song</COLLOC><COLLOC>word</COLLOC><COLLOC>name</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Working together the students have to <b>make</b> up a very short story using the verbs.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We were always <b>making</b> up songs on the bus.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He does this by <b>making</b> up new words which really do sound like what they're describing.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX><b>Make</b> up silly names for all members of your group which must be used at all times.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>rule</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>If something is not to my liking, even though it's a command of scripture and a ruling in the church, if does not suit me I will <b>make</b> my own rules up and act on them.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it up as one goes along</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Both fiction writers and film makers seem to <b>make it up as</b> they go along ; the reason, I suppose, is that history is "politically incorrect.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to say sth that is not true</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>By lunch they had seen enough to know I wasn't just <b>making</b> it up, I really could help their riding.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>She accuses him of <b>making</b> the whole thing up .
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>excuse</COLLOC><COLLOC>lie</COLLOC><COLLOC>story</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>I would <b>make</b> up some excuse not to go.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He even <b>made up</b> lies to cover for my absences.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>We also went down crocodile creek' where the instructors had <b>made</b> up a story that there was a croc to scare us.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to comprise sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>In some areas, girls <b>made</b> up 50 percent of all new pupils.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>However, extensions to domestic properties <b>make</b> up the vast majority of planning applications received in the Borough.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The telecommunications market <b>makes</b> up the main part of our business, contributing around a quarter of T-Systems ' total revenues.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>be made up of sth</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Most informed sources suggest a figure of 4.5 % of domestic waste is <b>made up of</b> baby nappies.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to prepare sth by putting different things together</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Every Saturday a team of people come to the church and <b>make up</b> parcels of foodstuffs to give to the poor.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Libraries <b>make up</b> collections of books in resource boxes, which teachers can use in the classroom, or in the library.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>After this I went home, <b>made up</b> my bundle, and left the town.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to make a bed ready to be slept in by putting sheets, covers etc on it or to prepare sth so that it can be used as a bed</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Grace will <b>make</b> up a bed for you behind the laundry.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It had separate bedrooms which was an improvement on last year's holiday which entailed <b>making</b> up beds in the lounge every night.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I'll find some sheets presently and you can <b>make</b> up a bed in the spare room.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="press"/><DOMAIN label="publ"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to arrange the different parts of an article etc on a page</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>The some of the page-bits (generally called components) are the same across several pages, so I don't really want to <b>make up</b> each new page by hand.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The practice of printing involved craftspeople with skill in assembling metal type, <b>making up</b> pages , inking, presswork, etc. And traditionally the appearance of most print was the result of these craftspeople applying their knowledge and skills in the origination stage.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to make an amount or number complete</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>I can only afford $ 18,200 and not a penny more. You will have to <b>make up</b> the rest.</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>shortfall</COLLOC><COLLOC>difference</COLLOC><COLLOC>deficit</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The redress considered appropriate was reinstatement to her AVC scheme, the company <b>making</b> up any shortfall in fund value.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Figure out what you need, what you have, and how to <b>make</b> up the difference.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Just 0.46 separated the two at the end with Alf just unable to <b>make</b> up the three point deficit in the last event.</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to do sth extra to compensate for not doing sth previously</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>If you have lost sleep , try <b>make it up</b> . Although we can funtion with only 4 hours sleep a night , most people function better with an average of 8 hours .</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>time</COLLOC><COLLOC>hours</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Staff can therefore start later than nominated or leave earlier than nominated in order to accommodate particular "one-off" requirements, and <b>make</b> the time up at a later (pre-agreed) date.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Whilst on a brigade training course personnel must make every effort to give fire cover during the night or <b>make up</b> the hours at the weekend according to the stations needs.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to become friends again after arguing</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="_0"/><ExCnt><EX>Unlike couples who have been together for years, blending couples have no experience of falling out and <b>making up</b> again.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There was no need for 2 fingers reallly - you two <b>make up</b> now.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT/><ExCnt><EX>Do you need to <b>make</b> up with someone?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX> Betty is said to be �thrilled� to have <b>made</b> up with her actress daughter.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>kiss and make up</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Ian guesses that Janet is having second thoughts about the engagement, but they <b>kiss and make up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>with</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Pauline seems determined not to forgive him, but she <b>makes up with</b> Dot.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But the England left back has refused to <b>make up with</b> Arsenal after the row following the "tapping up" scandal with Chelsea.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>McCartney went on to tell reporters he has officially <b>made up with</b> Yoko Ono after that falling out over how Lennon McCartney tracks should be credited.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it up </CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>I lost touch with Arthur . He stole my girl whose ambition was to make him cry . Then we <b>made it up</b> and corresponded a couple of times a year , taking it in turns to send each other a fiver on " loan " in remembrance of The Albert .</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>make it up with sb</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Review Let's be honest, we've seen this kind of film before - someone shallow and selfish learns that they're dying and has to <b>make it up</b> with their family and friends before they die.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><MEANING>to put make-up on sb</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>A friend of mine once asked me and another friend to <b>make him up</b>" just to see "what he'd look like.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>She must have spent half an hour <b>making herself up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Features: Noakes is <b>made</b> up to look like Henry VIII by the BBC Make Up department.</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make up to</PHRV><LabelGp><REGIST label="inf"/><TIME label="dat"/></LabelGp></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv_prep"/><MEANING>to behave in an over-friendly way to sb in order to get some advantage for oneself</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Whatever career or job avenue you follow there are ways to be successful . This does not necessarily mean <b>making up to</b> your boss or stitching up your colleagues . </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Sally had tried to <b>make up to</b> him once, by letter, in a bygone time, and had not made that mistake again.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Charlie is smitten with a man's wife in the park and <b>makes up to</b> her, only to be warned off severely by the husband (Ambrose).
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><LINK>make it up to sb</LINK></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt><PhrVCnt><PhrVGp><PHRV>make with</PHRV></PhrVGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="phr_v"/><GRAM code="v_adv"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><REGIST label="inf"/><STYLE label="spok"/></LabelGp><MEANING>to start producing, using or doing sth</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>He started to <b>make with</b> the romance talk in a big way.</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>Let's make with the ...</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Alright, enough of this jibber-jabber – let's make with the update!</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>C'mon Mark, stop being a douchebag and let's make with the tipping, okay? </EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrVCnt></PhrVBlk><CpdBlk><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>make believe</CPD><VarCnt><VAR>make-believe</VAR></VarCnt></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the action of pretending that sth is true or that things are much better than they really are</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Why not wander into a world of <b>make believe</b> at Anglesey Model Village or wonder at the spectacular creatures that live beneath our waters at the Anglesey Sea Zoo.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Psalm is depicting historical truth, not <b>make believe</b> or some kind of fairy tale.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Everybody who approves of sorting out problems by using fact and reason rather than <b>make-believe</b> and emotion will welcome the Prime Minister's speech today at the Royal Society.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>Yet she spent years living in the private hell of bulimia, trying to become like the glossy images in the <b>make-believe</b> world around her.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Rather than sitting down for an "educational" numbers game, parents should get down on the living room floor with their children and join in their <b>make-believe</b> games.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In the opening page, the model poses with her <b>make-believe</b> husband, son and daughter, all smiling effusively in front of a fireplace, its mantle covered with duck decoys.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to pretend that sth is true</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="that_0"/><ExCnt><EX>It was nice to see Mum again and the Pakistani cop was there, so I <b>made believe</b> I had an alibi.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>His new neighbour stops him and finds the perfect solution to keep his job: to <b>make believe</b> he's gay!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Then again many consumers are them who wanna <b>make believe</b> theyŽre quality women.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>make or break</CPD></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><VarCnt><VAR>make-or-break</VAR></VarCnt><MEANING>a situation in which sb/sth is success or fails completely</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>I really wanted this chance , but I was scared . It was <b>make or break</b> . </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But this season for them is almost a <b>make or break</b>, The pressures on them to perform and it will be tough for them, and if they get off to a good start it wont be easy for us to walk into the knock out stages. </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There is no second time around, this <b>is make or break</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>for</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>Yet while this is just another bench mark for Frazer, it's kind of <b>make-or-break for</b> Alicia Silverstone.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I think the first year of a baby's life <b>is make or break</b> for a couple really, even if it's your first, second, third, or sixth baby it never gets easier and your never prepared for each others reactions.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>For some arriving at college <b>is make or break</b> for their faith - many lose their way without the support of their family church; many others are asking questions and come to faith in Christ and get God's vision for their life after Uni.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>It is <b>make or break</b> time, every game is now effectively a cup final.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>And particularly that first lecture in any series -- a <b>make or break</b> occasion for many a student.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>When they return, they face what could be a <b>make or break</b> week for their increasingly beleagured boss, beginning with a televised clash at home to Plymouth Argyle before trips to Watford three days later and a Sunday lunchtime feast in the shape of the first East Anglian derby in two seasons.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="v"/><MEANING>to either make sb/sth very successful or make them fail completely</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRV code="NP"/><ExCnt><EX>Fussing over the details can <b>make or break</b> a new restaurant.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The accessories you put on can <b>make or break</b> your outfit.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There will always be someone over you who can <b>make or break</b> you in the industry.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>make-up artist</CPD><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="empl"/><DOMAIN label="cosm"/></LabelGp></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>sb whose job is to put make-up on people, especially in theatre, television etc</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>During the Wedding Fair celebrity <b>make-up artist</b> Jemma Kidd will be demonstrating the latest wedding day make-up trends on brides-to-be.</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>make-up</CPD><VarCnt><VAR>makeup</VAR></VarCnt></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="mass"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="cosm"/></LabelGp><MEANING>lipstick, eyeshadow, blusher etc</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>They are shown how to look after their skin and apply <b>make-up</b>.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The zombies are given lots of <b>make-up</b> to make them look more gruesome.</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Baby oil on cotton wool removes eye <b>make-up</b> very successfullly.</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>wear make-up</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>Lower School pupils are not permitted to wear <b>make-up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt><FwkSupPrepCnt><SUPPREP>in</SUPPREP><ExCnt><EX>It wouldn't do for a chief inspector, but Julian Clary looks lovely <b>in make-up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSupPrepCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>Prior to the event, beauty students will be carrying out <b>make-up</b> demonstrations for the public.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>bag</COLLOC><COLLOC>remover</COLLOC><COLLOC>effect</COLLOC><COLLOC>tip</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Get my <b>make-up</b> bag out of my bag.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Use a light <b>make-up</b> remover specifically for the eyes and, if you like to use an eye cream, choose a light formulation.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>There are some other nice touches to the film, including some good <b>make-up</b> effects for the dead bodies.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Using these <b>make-up</b> tips will help you minimise any distortion caused by your lenses.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="TV-rad"/><DOMAIN label="theat"/><DOMAIN label="cine"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the place at a television studio, theatre etc where people have their make-up done</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>When you get in they'll take you to<b>make-up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But I can remember her sitting in <b>make-up</b>, saying' I don't understand.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the composition of a group or whole</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The ISAF is already training the first battalion of an Afghan National Guard - about 600 strong and with an ethnic <b>make-up</b> that reflects that of Afghanistan itself.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The context for childrenâs participation takes cognisance of the influences of schooling, the exclusion of children from the workplace, as well as the influences of technology, the media, and the changes in family <b>make-up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Home Secretary 's Advisory Committee under the old 1876 Act was dominated by vivisectors and vivisection industry interests such as animal and equipment suppliers ; the new Animal Procedures Committee would have the same <b>make-up</b> .</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>4. Population The size and <b>make-up</b> of the population affects demand.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The final <b>make-up</b> of the team will be determined at a series of trials at the famous bobsleigh run in St Moritz, Switzerland.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>As the <b>make-up</b> of the nursing workforce is continually changing, why oh why does it seem that we are fighting a losing battle?
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="biol"/><DOMAIN label="genet"/></LabelGp><MEANING>the composition of a living thing</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Each of us is born with a unique genetic <b>make-up</b> that influences the development of our individual personality.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Unfortunately, all the conditioning in the world won't alter the chemical <b>make-up</b> in your body.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>The organism functions normally if it functions, without disturbance, in accord with the biological and physiological <b>make-up</b> of the human body.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>" The team set out to understand why a complex gene in wheat called PH1 controlled the <b>make-up</b> of the plant.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Due to their biological <b>make-up</b>, nearly all women will develop noticeable cellulite at some point in life.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the combination of qualities that make a person's character</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>What constitutes a moral agent ? According to many the answer is that she must have a certain psychological <b>make-up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Perhaps people who embrace such mechanistic nihilism have a fundamentally different <b>make-up</b> to those who need to find comfort in more optimistic theories.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>' You would think there would have to be something innate in the <b>make-up</b> of a person like a McEnroe because a lot of the population could practise as much as he did, yet never reach his level of performance,' says Bruce Abernethy, a sports psychologist at the University of Queensland in Australia.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But that feeling of loss never really leaves you . It 's just there all the time , no matter how healed you think you are . It becomes a part of your <b>makeup</b> .</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>They are a most important part of your mental and emotional <b>make-up</b> and powerfully affect your actions.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><LabelGp><DOMAIN label="publ"/><DOMAIN label="press"/></LabelGp><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the activity of arranging words, pictures etc on a page</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Technology old and new: left, former editor Eric Pigott at the printing works; right, some of the computers that have replaced the typesetters for page <b>make-up</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/><DOMAIN label="edu"/></LabelGp><MEANING>a special exam taken by a student that has missed or failed an exam</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Excused absences (with documentation) will be allowed a <b>makeup</b> which must be taken within 48 hours of the scheduled date.</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE/><CollocGp><COLLOC>exam</COLLOC><COLLOC>test</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Does anyone know the procedure for makeup exams? </EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Can I take a <b>makeup</b> test later?
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp><MEANING>an event that is a substitute for a previous event that was cancelled</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Clinton's overnight stay in Denmark was a <b>makeup</b> for a visit he canceled after he tore his knee tendon in March.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Monday's race was a <b>makeup</b> of the opening race of the round-robin, which was abandoned because of 25 knot winds and heavy seas Feb. 14.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><COLLOCTYPE/><CollocGp><COLLOC>day</COLLOC><COLLOC>game</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Monday was a <b>makeup</b> day for school time students lost after Hurricane Marilyn hit last September.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>What looked like a nice four-day break has been filled with a <b>makeup</b> game against Washington on April 6.</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt><CpdCnt><CpdGp><CPD>make-work</CPD><LabelGp><REGION label="AmE"/></LabelGp></CpdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>work that is given to sb so that they have sth to do, not because it really needs doing</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>This is not <b>make-work</b>, in fact some writers admit that pitching their stories improves their writing.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>In short , what is the point of this ? Other than <b>make-work</b> for Government employees .</EX></ExCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><ExCnt><EX>Her style of government has turned out to be a marvellous <b>make-work</b> scheme for political scientists, contemporary historians and political commentators.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Bush's new rules would lead the states to create massive <b>make-work</b> projects that would devour state and federal money while providing little in the way of valuable work experience.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></CpdCnt></CpdBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
