<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="20"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>maker</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>the person or company who makes something</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>handmade in England Hyacinth Design - Furniture made from woven Water Hyacinth grown in Thailand Interior Supply Ltd - Provides the Interior Designer with a complete one-stop shopping service i tre Furniture - Cutting edge furniture that bridges the gap between sculpture and the functional Isokon Plus - Classic and contemporary furniture J Robert Scott - The encyclopaedia of style James Codrington - Dedicated to designing and making fine contemporary furniture Jan Cavelle - Supplies high quality furniture to the interior design trade Johnny Hawkes - Artists and engineers in wood, metal and plastics Jonathon Markovitz - Designer and <b>maker</b> of beautiful contemporary furniture Katie Walker Furniture - Each design combines function with a strong sculptural interpretation of its structure Ligne Roset - A wide range of sleek designs Make Furniture - Contemporary furniture made by British craftsmen Mark Brazier Jones - One of the UK's leading lights in contemporary furniture design Matthew Burt - An independent designer/maker, unconstrained by manufacturing dogma Mufti - Smart, casual and comfortable Nicholas Haslam - Furniture items are generally in stock for immediate despatch Paul Carruthers Design - Contemporary furniture with short batch production Paul Gower Furniture - Design furniture for
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The <b>makers</b> of the Plan B morning-after pill applied yesterday to have the drug made available from pharmacists without the need for a doctor's prescription throughout the United States.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The copyrights in websites (which are in effect databases regardless of content) are owned by their <b>makers</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="comb"/><MEANING>a person or machine that makes the thing specified</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>The trade flourished until about 1795 and one of the best known jewellery <b>makers</b>, John Worralow, was appointed steel jeweller to George III in 1782.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I seriously considered bringing my fairly large popcorn <b>maker</b> to Cambridge but then balefully decided that it would take up too much space in the car.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Sarah is also a member of the steering group of the London and Women Planning forum, which attempts to bring together policy <b>makers</b>, urban planners and academics in order to change and improve the position of women in relation to planning issues (see www.lwpf.org ). In addition to all this she also works as an editorial assistant in the Medical Geography office of Social Science and Medicine.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkSenCnt><SUBFORM>the Maker</SUBFORM><VarCnt><VAR>our/his etc Maker</VAR></VarCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>God</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Hopeless of the future, I wished but this -- that my <b>Maker</b> had that night thought good to require my soul of me while I slept; and that this weary frame, absolved by death from further conflict with fate, had now but to decay quietly, and mingle in peace with the soil of this wilderness.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>A poet may describe the beauty and the grandeur of Nature, the flowers of the spring and the harvests of autumn, the vicissitudes of the tide and the revolutions of the sky, and praise the <b>Maker</b> for his works, in lines which no reader shall lay aside.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Not a whole Reform Bill, a whole French Revolution executed for his behoof alone: nothing but God the <b>Maker</b> can emancipate him, by making him anew.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrBlk><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>meet one's maker</PHR><LabelGp><STYLE label="euph"/></LabelGp></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to die</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>She should count her blessing, but what comes around goes around, she will have to meet her <b>maker</b> just like the rest of us Posted by: Carol | July 3, 2006 02:27 PM Didn't Peter Crouch once haved two page three girls fighting over him?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Of course, soldiers about to meet their <b>maker</b> might have little time to gaze upon the pretty Vale of Pewsey.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He flashes me a giant smile and holds the calendar up. What do you gonna do with them pictures?, the elderly man asks. Well, Im gonna meet my <b>maker</b> soon, and I think these might make my meantime just a little more comfortable. He thumbs through the calendar. Pretty, eh? The man exhales a puff of smoke and shrugs.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt></PhrBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
