<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="30"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>makeover</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><MEANING>something done to make someone or something look much better</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Does your web site need a <b>makeover</b>?
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The Quays, Debenhams and Peter Mark have teamed up with the Newry Reporter to offer one lucky reader the chance to be a part of this exciting venture and win a fantastic <b>makeover</b> just in time for the Christmas Party Season!
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Plans include a <b>makeover</b> of the existing building and the construction of a' glazed wing' to house a brasserie-style café and restaurant.
</EX></ExCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>have</COLLOC><COLLOC>undergo</COLLOC><COLLOC>get</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The interior had a <b>makeover</b> in the Eighties with Egyptian tiling and decoration, a new children's pool and better changing facilities in the basement.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The brand underwent a major <b>makeover</b> in 2001, with new bottle and label designs introducing a more contemporary feel whilst retaining the essential components that have drawn consumers to Piat d'Or during its 24 year history.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Each week one person (and nine times out of 10 it's a woman) gets a complete <b>makeover</b> with the aim of making them look ' ten years younger'.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>give sb/sth</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>The rundown shop was given a <b>makeover</b> and now resembles a Victorian dairy with a white and black checkered floor, and stock beautifully presented on gingham cloth and in straw-filled barrels.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>complete</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>Enjoy a Super experience, when you arrive at the venue, you will be given a complete <b>makeover</b>, qualified make-up artists will apply your make up and then you will have your hair done, you will then have the chance to wear an outfit for your photo-shoot or you can bring your own favourite outfit, necklace ear-rings and furs can also be used for your photo.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>Cadets Give Local Garden a Makeover A local elderly care home has had garden <b>makeover</b>, thanks to Strathclyde Police.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Wal-Mart claimed that it has only now allowed a trade union, because there had been no earlier requests for one. www.walmart.com 23 November 2004 Wal-Mart To Improve Image Value retailer Wal-Mart is to give itself an image <b>makeover</b> with a concerted campaign to improve its standing with the US public.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Based on the US show Extreme Makeover, which attracts over 20 million viewers, the show would give six families a life-changing home <b>makeover</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_premod"/><FwkCollocCnt><CollocGp><COLLOC>show</COLLOC><COLLOC>programme</COLLOC></CollocGp><ExCnt><EX>" A move on from boring <b>makeover</b> shows, The Reclaimers is the ultimate in prosumer telly ... Like eating a ready meal while watching Nigella it makes you believe you could do the same before shelving the idea somewhere between watching fantastically skilled homeboy-restorer Sean at work and the credits "The Guardian" After flocks of dreary reality property shows, an antidote: this smart series ... "Sunday Telegraph  Fortunately, next on BBC2 was the latest episode of The Reclaimers  a much gentler series, but also a much better one.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Traditional Garden If you watch a lot of garden <b>makeover</b> programmes, you'd be forgiven for thinking that traditional gardens are out of style.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkCollocCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt></DEnt></Entry>
