<Entry xmlns="urn:NEID" xmlns:d="urn:NEID" level="50"><DEnt><HwdGp><HWD>making</HWD></HwdGp><FwkSenCnt><POS code="n"/><GRAM code="uncount"/><MEANING>the process of making or producing something</MEANING><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="PP_X"/><STRSTAT>of</STRSTAT><ExCnt><EX>This whisky stock, reflecting the skill, knowledge and experience that has gone into the <b>making</b> of BenRiach is testimony to the many years stretching back to the 19th century during which the distillery built its reputation.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>- New faces are brought to the screen - Local issues are presented in informative and entertaining ways- Health education and economic resources in the community are promoted- Local talent and initiatives are celebrated- Participation is inclusive of all under represented communities (whether geographical, racial, ethnic, cultural or generational) NvTv also actively seeks to widen the community's involvement in broadcasting and to encourage active participation in the <b>making</b> of programmes for local broadcast.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt><FwkStrCnt><STRN code="N_mod"/><ExCnt><EX>It is important to remember that for all the high-octane ideas and practices that hallmark Robertoâs wine <b>making</b>, his ethos is clear.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>At the same time, rules setting out transitional arrangements from the old decision <b>making</b> and review scheme to the new DMA one come into force. [footnote 2] Guidance has been issued to local authorities (LAs) on the new scheme in the form of standard LA guidance and special' Communications Bulletins ' from the Appeals Service. [footnote 3] This article will outline the rules, identify the main differences from other DMA rules, and describe the transitional rules and especially pertinent parts of the guidance.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>He considered that the poor attendance at annual meetings was an indication of parents reluctance to be involved in policy <b>making</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkStrCnt></FwkSenCnt><FwkMWEBlk><PhrBlk><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>have the makings of sth</PHR><VarCnt><VAR>have all the makings of sth</VAR></VarCnt></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to have the qualities necessary to become something</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>He had the <b>makings</b> of a brilliant golfer, but a combination of bad luck and inconsistent play invariably robbed him of the fruits of his skill.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Oh the glamour..oh the humiliation of Emily Drew's attendance at a film screening By Irish_cailin Attendance at a Press Screening &amp; Press Conference It's official; I do not have the <b>makings</b> of a successful journalist.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>It has all the <b>makings</b> of a Christmas classic, Santa, a cute kid and a feel-good ending, but if you're expecting an' It's A Wonderful Life ' type Christmas schmaltz-fest, you're way off the mark.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>in the making</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>in the process of being developed or made</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>This tragedy brings the world's attention to a disaster that, unfortunately, has been in the <b>making</b> for decades.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>If you wish to see a city in the <b>making</b>, employing an integrated land-use and transport planning strategy in practice, now is the time to come and visit this splendid city by the sea.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>But is Manchester United's new boy a hero in the <b>making</b>?
</EX></ExCnt><ChunkCnt><CHUNK>history in the making</CHUNK><ExCnt><EX>The Last Governor Category: Non-Fiction UK Publisher: Time Warner UK Publication Date: 10/07/97 During the final five years of British rule in Hong Kong, Jonathan Dimbleby witnessed history in the <b>making</b>.
</EX></ExCnt></ChunkCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>be of one's own making</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>if a situation, especially a bad one, is of your own making, you have caused it</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>Councillor McLeod said the service "is dogged by financial problems that are not of its own <b>making</b>" and that the OIC could be doing more to help out.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Both Jayston and Langford underplay the last scene beautifully, which means that while the listener desperately sympathises with Mel's fate they can even have the odd pang of compassion for the Valeyard, despite the situation being one of his own <b>making</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>I wish all party goers could have witnessed the sheer blood, sweat and tears that was going down in the small techie's room downstairs from the main hall as Arathorn, a volunteer who'd flown in from the UK just to help with the party, led a team that seemed to be having to cope with one minor disaster after another that was not of their own <b>making</b>.
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>The first chance was all of his own <b>making</b>, as he robbed Steve Robinson on the edge of the box and fired the ball goalwards.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt><PhrCnt><PhrGp><PHR>be the making of sb/sth</PHR></PhrGp><FwkSenCnt><MEANING>to be something which makes someone or something succeed</MEANING><ExCnt><EX>It was a painful time for Sheridan, but it ended up being the <b>making</b> of him .
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Theresa knew her daughter didn't want to be a teacher, but it might be the <b>making</b> of her ...
</EX></ExCnt><ExCnt><EX>Cables and Interconnects The right selection of cables can be the <b>making</b> of a good system, here's how.
</EX></ExCnt></FwkSenCnt></PhrCnt></PhrBlk></FwkMWEBlk></DEnt></Entry>
